THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 10 1905.
3
NORWAY AND SWEDEN.
NORWAY’S PREPARATIONS.
OUTLOOK NOW HOPEFUL.
Stockholm, September 18.

Travellers report that last week Norway was energetically preparing for war by constructing temporary fortifications on the frontier, cutting down trees and barricading the roads. Nearly all the troops in the central and frontier districts seemed to be mobilised.	(Reuter)

Christiania, September 18.

Relief is felt here at the peaceful outlook, but hope is expressed that peace has not been too dearly bought.	(Reuter)
RUSSIAN ADMINISTRATION.
COUNCIL TO BE FORMED.

St. Petersburg, September 18.

The Tsar has ordered the Commission that is arranging the meeting of the National Assembly to examine a project for the formation of a Council of Ministers under the Premier, who, with the Minister of War, Marine and Foreign Affairs will have the sole right of reporting to the Emperor.	(Reuter)

St. Petersburg, September 18.

The Tsar has ordered the formation of a Council of Ministers who will deal with all administrative measures.	(Havas)
FRANCE AND GERMANY.
GERMANY PROCRASTINATES.

Paris, September 18.

The delay in the Franco-German negotiations on the subject of Morocco has evoked a strong protest, complaining of the German procrastination, from the "Temps.” (Reuter)
Jena, September 18.

M. Bebel, inaugurating the Socialistic Congress, condemned the provocative policy of Germany concerning Morocco.	(Havas)
BOSPHORUS BEING FORTIFIED.
RUSSIA DISPLEASED.

London, September 18.

Fortifications are being rapidly constructed on the Bosphorus as a result of the scare occasioned at Constantinople by the Potemkin’s mutiny. These fortifications are causing great displeasure in Russia, and it is understood that a protest has already been made.

(Reuter)
THE CALABRIAN CATASTROPHE. 	RELIEF MEASURES.

Catanzaro, September 18.

The erection of huts, and other measures for the relief of the sufferers are proceeding actively. The difficulties are enormous owing to the great distances in a hilly country, and the dearth of workmen.	(Reuter)
ACCIDENT INSURANCE CONGRESS.
Vienna September 18. The international congress of insurance against accidents has been opened. M. Mil-lerande is assisting.	(Havas)
THE TSARS CRUISE.
St. Petersburg September 18. The Tsarita and children accompanied the Tsar on his yacht. The cruise was purely for pleasure.	(Reuter)
M. WITTE IN FRANCE.
LOCAL AND GENERAL
San Stefano Casino.—A grand ball, for subscribers only, has been arranged for Saturday next at the San Stefano Casino.
The Egyptian Directory, administrative and commercial, for the year 1906 will appear in November. The price of the volume will be P.T. 50.
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Ghezireh district of Cairo during to-morrow night and at dawn of the 21st inst will be poisoned by the police.
Asile Rudolph. — Dr. W. Birbari and M. Alexandre Birbari have each contributed P.T. 100 to the funds of the Asile Rudolph in memo ry of the late Signor Salvatore Felice.
Suez Canal.—5 vessels passed through the Canal on the 15th inst, 3 of which were British and 2 Gorman. The receipts for the day were frs. 194,443.22, making the total from the lst inst. frs 4,191,495.40.
Cherbourg, September 18. M. Witte has disembarked and left for Paris.

(Havas)

DEATH OF AN M.P.
Rumoured Cotton Press Strike. — Rumours arc afloat as to the outbreak of a strike among the workmen employed in the cotton pressing factories. Up to the moment of going to press we have received no information on the subject that goes beyond hearsay.
The Italian Fete.—To-morrow being the occasion of the Italian national fete, a special entertainment, commencing at 9 p.m., will be given at the Alhambra Theatre, and the proceeds will again be devoted to the aid of the victims of the earthquake. Too first part of the programme will consist of short plays, the second part of a firework display, and the third part of a vocal and instrumental concert.
The British Association.—The members of the British Association, which has been holding its annual meeting this year in South Africa, will probably pay a short visit to Cairo on their way home. The party went out by the West Coast, and will return by the East Coast in the S.S. Durham Castle, which was specially chartered by the Association. The vessel is due to arrive at Suez on or about the 5th proximo, and Messrs. Thos. Cook & Son are awaiting a cablegram from Aden as to the number who will leave the steamer at Suez and, after visiting Cairo, rejoin her at Port Said.
The Earthquake in Calabria. — The organising committee for the relief fund for the victims of the Calabrian earthquake asks us to state that a Charity sale and fete champ-6tre will take place on Sunday, 1st October, at the Theatre des Ambassadenrs at Ghezireh, commencing at 3.30 p.m e express our hope that the British community of the capital will generously respond to the efforts being made to send succour to the thousands of homeless and starving people in Southern Italy. The committee will strive to make the entertainment as attractive as possible and in a few days we shall give a list of the amusements that will be provided for the occasion.
PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.
H.H. Prince Mohamed Ali will leave Constantinople by the Khedivial S.S. Ismailia, whioh is due on Tuesday next
Sir Vincent Corbett will arrive in Cairo on the 9th October.
El Lewa E. E. Bernard Pasha, financial Secretary, Sudan Government, is expected to return to Cairo very shortly.
Abdullah Bey Sfer is expected to return from leave towards the end of this month.
London, September 18.

Sir Robert Gunter, M.P., is dead.(Reuter)

Sir Robert Gunter, of Wetherby Lodge, Yorkshire, was born in London on November 9, 1831, and was educated at Rugby. At the age of twenty he joined the 4th Dragoon Guards and served with that regiment through the Crimean War (medal and clasps and Turkish medal), and later joined the Yorkshire hussars. He married Jane Marguerite,daughter of Thomas Benyon of Gledhow Hall,Yorkshire. He was raised to the baronetcy in 1901. Sir Robert Genter was well-known and greatly respectedn‘Yorkshire,and was for many years Conservative member of Parliament for the Barkston Ash Division. He took a great interest in the welfare of the Wetherby district, where he was chairman of the Petty Sessions, District Council, and Board of Guardians, occupying the latter position since 1872. He was also a keen agriculturalist, and was known all over the world as the breeder of the Wetherby shorthorn and the Wetherby Duchess cattle.
AUGUST CUSTOMS RETURNS.
The Duke and Duchess d’Airola, who havear-rived in London from Naples, are staying at the Hotel Cecil, where his Excellency Mohsen Pasha, from Cairo, is also in residence.
Captain M. J. Hamilton, Lancashire Fusiliers, who has arrived in Egypt from England, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army with the rank of Bimbashi,and is posted to the 2nd Battalion.
Captain P.F.R. Anley, Nottinghamshire and Derbyshire Regiment, who has arrived in Egypt from Singapore, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army with the rank of Bimbashi, and is posted to the 10th Sudanese.
Obtainable frs« mrj Raapaatabla Firm I» Gaum. Aawvamu k na Otherwise upgig Is

v.nimstr, r. mkaluf b*

Ou»r	U« Bot Kite, Amuimu
INCREASED EXPORTS.
As was the case last month the Customs report is again out early, and those who predicted that the administration would be unable to “keep it up” will be pleasantly disappointed. The imports for the past month totalled L.E. 1,803,691 against LE. 1,626,093 in August 1904, showing a decided increase. The imports for the period commencing on January 1 and ending on August 31, amounted to L.E. 12,740,913 against LE. 11,831,292 in the corresponding period of the past year, an increase of L.E. 909,621 in favor of 1905.

The exports, which had showed an advance for the month of July over the figures of July 1904, maintained and increased their lead over August's figures in 1904. In that month the total exports amounted to LE. 800,024. In August 1905, goods amounting to LB. 1,165,510 left the country, a balance of L.E. 365,486. The export figures for the first eight months of the year still show a certain falling off, the total value of goods exported being LE. 11,949,871 against LE. 12,687,678 in the corresponding period in 1904 but another two or three returns like those of August and July, and Egypt’s exports will show an increase on the whole year.

In August, imports from Great Britain and the British Mediterranean possessions amounted  to LE. 602,049, against HE. 511,691 in August 1904, while for the two-thirds of the year they amounted to L.E. 4,362,501 against L.E. 4,037,635 daring the corresponding period of the past year. French, Russian and Turkish imports show a similar increase for the eight months, but Russian imports fell off last month totalling only L.R. 43,541 against L.E. 64,795 in August last year. In the export tables for the month Great Britain shows an increase of over 80%. France, Germany, and the U.S.A. have also been good customers.

In the period comprised between New Year’s day 1905 and August 31, the only notable increase of Egyptian exports to any one country is to be found in the oase of Turkey and the U. S. A. Great Britain (L E. 5,806,705 against LE 6,214,459 in 1904) Russia L E. 673.615 against L.E. 948,558, and above all Italy with only L.E. 326,375 against L.E. 705,308 are all notable examples of the decrease in value daring this period of Egyptian exports.
Lieutenant Huntley Walsh, Royal Navy,who has arrived, in Egypt, has been taken on the strength of the Egyptian Army with the rank of Bimbashi, and has been posted to the Sudan Government.
BECKS CO'S PILSNER BEER
REMARKABLE SWIMMING FEAT.
CONCORDAT PREVENTIF GRANTED
(By telephone).

This morning the Commercial Chamber of the Cairo Mixed Court of First Instance decided to grant the Sucreries Company benefit of the Concordat Preventif. The chief feature of the audience was the extremely dear and able speech on behalf of the application of this measure which was delivered by Maitre Carton de Wiart and lasted half an hour. At the conclusion of the speech Judge Tuck, who presided over the audience, Asked if there was any opposition. None was made and the Court adjourned at 11 a.m. to deliberate on this and several other cases. At 12.45 p.m. Judge Tuck announced that the Concordat Preventif had been granted and ordered the company to send their books into court within eight days. No mention was made whether the names of the three liquidators submitted to the court, viz. Sir Elwin Palmer, Harari Pasha and M. Dubourg, had been accepted or not. Fall particulars will be given to-morrow.

• •

The decision of the court is fortunate from every point of view. It is the only possible means of preventing a terrible crash which would not only cause heavy losses to many of the company's creditors and to the shareholders, but would ruin the native cultivators of cane. This provisional judgment will not prevent the Parquet from having the compulsionary winding up declared later so as to take criminal proceedings against any director or official found at fault, should events demand this course.

We publish on page 4 the balance sheet of the Sucreries Company as filed before the Mixed Tribunals on Saturday. We understand that certain errors were to he found in the balance sheet as published by one of on Cairo contemporaries, which, while not invalidating the general result, might cause a certain confusion in the mind of the reader.
Mr. George W. Poss, an American by birth, resident in Cairo, and chief engineer of the Egyptian Cotton Mills in Cairo, having heard many people say that to cross the Nile near the bridges was very dangerous and almost impossible, thought he would try the experiment himself, and succeeded with comparative ease. A day so after, he swam from the new bridge at Old Cairo to Basus, which is a small town eleven and a quarter miles distant from Cairo. This feat was accomplished b two hours.

Accompanying him to prevent any mishap, and to carry Mr. Poss’s clothes, was an employe of the cotton mills named Joseph de Santis.

At Old Cairo they had some difficulty in getting a boat, the Arabs refusing when they learned of his intention of swimming down the river; bat crossing the river by the ferry they managed to obtain a boat. Reading the centre of the river Mr. Poss undressed, and greatly to the astonishment of the Arabs plunged into the water.

A strong wind was blowing at the time up the river, and the boat was unable to keep pace with the swimmer ; yet they managed to keep Mr. Poss in view when he passed under the new bridge at Old Cairo, and as far as the bridge at Kasr-el-Nil, after which they lost sight of him entirely. At this point J. De Santis left the boat and taking Mr. Poss’s clothes went on to Rod el Farag thinking he would find him there, and it was not without some misgivings that he failed to do so, for no one had seen a man swim past that place.

At this point J. De Santis gave up the search and Mr. Poss was left to do his best in a bathing suit. At Basus Mr. Poss went ashore, being afraid of taking cramp with no boat near to render help ; and Amin Effendi, Omdeh of Basus, kindly lent him some clothes and sent some of his men with a boat to take him back to Cairo. If the conditions are favorable, so that a boat can keep pace with him, Mr. Poss hopes very soon to attempt to swim from Cairo to the Barrage.
esbekieh gardens.
By kind permission of Lieut. Colonel C. J. Markham and Officers the Band of the 1st Bn. King’s Royal Rifles will perform the following programme of music at the Esbekieh Gardens to-morrow, Tuesday evening, commencing at 9 o’clock.

1 March	Pomp and Circumstance No. I	Elgar.

4 Overture	Poet and Peasanr	Suppe.

I Selection	Florodors	Stuart.

4 Japanese Dance			Clayton,

6 Military Tattoo	La Retraite Militaire	Wely.

0 Selection	The Mikado	8ulllran.

T Gavotte	Passion Flowers	Fleutini.

8 Valse....Lustige (By Special Request)...Vollstedt.

Regimental March,—Khedivial Anthem God Save the King

Thomas Brown, Bandmaster
STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
The S.S. Egyptian of the Westcott and Laurance Line left Malta yesterday and is due at Alexandria on Friday with general cargo from Antwerp and London.
THE SUCRERIES.
THE CHOLERA SCARE.
NOTES FROM. PORT SAID.
FIRST OUTWARD TROOPSHIP.

(From our Correspondent).

Port Said, Monday.

H. M. transport Assays (Commander F. H. Saymour), the first outward troopship of the season, arrived at Port 8aid on Sunday morning from Southampton and left in the afternoon bound for Bombay. She has on board the 17th Lancers (Colonel Portal) composed of 21 officers and 560 men ; also drafts of the 9th and 12th Lancers, 10th and 15th Hussars, 1st Dragoons, 6b Dragoon Guards, and details, making a total of 1,303 of all ranks.

The officer commanding the troops is Lt-Col. J. H. da B. Travers, 1st Batt, S. Wales Borderers.

PERSONAL.

Mr. Claudius, the postmaster of this town, is returning to Port Said at the end of the month to resume his official duties. Mr. Harrington, who has been officiating in his absence, is to return to Suez on Mr. Claudius’ arrival
PASSENGER LIST.
ARRIVALS.
Le psquebot Tebe, de la Cie Florio Rubat-tbo arrive bier de Gknes et Mesabe avait k bord:

Mme Parvis Ferero et sa fille, M. et Mma L F. Peney, M. Lias, insp. Swanson, Bakry Bey, C. Messiah, M. et Mme H. R. Soott, M. et Mme Mosoonas, G. Bid, G. Fomagalli, L. Antoury, A. G. Tome, 4 foeora, P. Operti, M. R. Collbgord, eceurs Landi, H. Waker, Bianca Brandani, Rev. Pkre Taccetti, V. Fiaski, M. C. Drosso Bey et famille, G.Savidi, Mile Lassalle, Mme Paoe, M. V. Sabatelli et famille, M. et Mme Maggio, Olivia Jelo, Ester Jelo, A. Mor-purgo, Mme Celoua et sa fille et 93 passagers de Smecl&s^
The recent outbreak of cholera in Russia and Germany has caused quite a scare throughout Europe, and it behoves the Sanitary Department to take prompt measures to prevent the dread malady appearing in Egypt with the return of the pilgrims from the Holy Places of Islam next season. Thera is no denying the fact that the chief homes of cholera are firstly British India, where the disease is endemic, and secondly the Hedjaz, where, however, it assumes an epidemic form. Of recent years Egypt has been visited by cholera on three different occasions. The first visitation was in 1883, when, according to the official returns, it claimed over 28,000 victims. The second outbreak was in 1895, when there were 18,133 deaths from the disease, and the third was three years ago, when the number of deaths recorded was close on 84,000. These figures are those famished by the Sanitary Department, but doubtless they are rather under than over the mortality in each case. It is worthy of note that the disease in this country has invariably broken oat in the hot month, and disappeared with the advent of cold weather, so that it is reasonable to assume that we shall be spared any visitation this year. The matter came last week before the Quarantine Board of Alexandria, which decided that no measures were at present necessary against arrivals from the northern ports of Europe.

This last invasion of Western Europe seems to have come from India, sweeping slowly and, almost unobserved, over Bast Europe, then through Galicia, Poland and East Prussia until it reached Dantzio, and lastly Hamburg Any introduction into Egypt through Europe seems somewhat remote, and there is no record that at any of the previous visitations it came from that quarter. On the contrary, each time it appeared in this country it was conclusively proved that it reached ns from the Red Sea ports, and it is in that direction that the sanitary authorities should turn their attention. The Quarantine Board should see that the utmost vigilance is exercised at Tor and Suez on the return of Egyptian pilgrims after the next cold weather, and it is to this board that the country looks for protection against another invasion of cholera. In our opinion there does not seem at present the slightest came for any alarm.
SPORT AND PLAY.
THE PRISONS DEPARTMENT.
The Tanzim service, having decided to macadamise the roads over which are to be laid the new lines and extensions of the Cairo Tramway Company, has requested the Prisons Department to doable its usual supply of macadam. Consequent on this demand the number of prisoners ocoupied in this work at the prison of Abou Zaabel has been considerably increased.

Two years ago the Ministry of the Interior promulgated an arrete conferring on the Prisons service the right of pardoning such prisoners as had served three quarters of their term and whose conduct had been exemplary daring their detention, exception being, however, made in the case of those who had been found guilty of poisoning animals and burning crops. The Prisons Department having recently asked the above Ministry whether the act of pardon was to be also extended to those of the prisoners who are detained on charges of incendiarism of houses and shounas, has received a reply in the negative.
	200	500	600	
	yds.	yds.	yds.	Total
Sgt. Wiggins	32	34	31	97
Aotg. Sgt. Maj. Qiiok 31		31	26	88
Col Sgt Gocdy	32	32	23	87
Sgt Thame	28	80	27	85
„ Goff	82	28	25	85
Col. Sgt. Holley	25	27	26	78
., „ A'dworth	32	22	21	75
Sgt Harper	27	25	20	72
	239	229	199	667
	200	500	600	
	yds.	yds.	yds.	Total
Mr. Waddiugton	32	29	24	85
„ Lucas	28	30	25	83
„ Diokson	30	31	19	80
„ Carlisle	84	27	19	80
„ Broomfield	26	25	27	78
„ Sohihzzi	28	20	24	72
„ Lovell	22	24	19	65
„ Riokards	26	18	18	62
	226	201	175	605

The range will be open forpractioe on S*tar-day next, 23rd inst from 8 p.m.
ALEXANDRIA SPORTING CLUB.
The following is the programme of musio to be played at the Race Meeting ou Thursday.

1 March—Flghtlnv thro’ to Victory- Fischer.

1 Overture—Ooawiocal—Muller.

S Va'eo -Tho Grenadiers—WaMUufel.

« Pcena—La benediction dec Polgnarda -Mejerbeer.

S Garotte—Denxieme—Albaraal.

8 Air and Ballet— Sldonie— 4 tnlllon.

T Morceaux Mignon—Palut d’Amour-Klgar.

8 Selection-La FoopAe—Audran.

O TWn.m. —	Mflt—g"1

10 Galop -Port Horn—Kami*.

Khedivial Anthem.—God 8av«The King.

S. Does, Bandmaster.

8. Royal Berkshire Regiment.

WINDSOR HOTEL “sa*

Tafcte tf'Hata LauhMH 4 Dlaaavt SsnM mm ilia Tiwsi.

ORCHBSTRA PLAYS 6 TO 11.90 P.M
LA LIQUIDATION DAIRA
KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.

REGATTA.

The handicap for tomorrow’s raoe is the same as last week.

Class I. Course A.

Class II. Coarse M.

BRITISH RIFLE CLUB.

8ERQt3. 2nd KOYAL BBRK8. REGT, t>. B. R. C. (ALEXANDRIA).

This match was shot off last Saturday under somewhat unfavorable conditions, the wind being very strong and trioky at times and the dast being blown into the competitors' faces ; scoring, consequently, was irregular

The Ssrgeaut8 won by the large margin of 62 points. #

Scores:

SERGEANTS 2nd ROYAL BERKS.
Anglo-Awerican Nile Steamers

J* flOTSIL COMPAXY.

1UER TRAI8P0RT OF 003D8 KTWEfl UUktOM i 0»l*

TIim SalllM* a-Waak.

AfmUe mt AlemmmkHm:-

uiiAMtu warn wawhwi
LE PROCES DBS PRINCES
(Suite et Fin)

Par ces motifs,

et tous autree k supplier en plaidant:

Entendre dire poor droit qae lout le surplat da prix de veuto dee biene Daira aprks ram-boa reement de la dette gdndrale da la Delia Sauieh et aprks remboursement de toutas tom-rnes pouvant fit re dues au GouvernmMnt Egyptian et aprh defalcation de toutes tom-mes revenant d la Daira Saniek Oompany Limited par tuite dengagement prit k ton profit en vue de la liquidation dee ditt biene et enfin apfb remboursement de tout Jrait de toute nature inhdrents k la gestion dee dita biens par la Daira Sanieh de S.A. le Khddive, appartient aux requtfrants htfritiexs de fee SA.

I	small Pacha, Khddive d’Egypte, exclasivement et entoute preprint A

Entendre en oonsdqaenoe dire etddolarer que le Credit Fonder Egyptian, la Daira Sanieh Company Limited et la Delia de 8. A le Khedive devront ohacan pour oe qai le ooooeme ddbattre aveo lea reqodrants h^ritiers de S.A. Ismail Paofaa tons oomptes afferent* k la liquidation dee biens de la Daira Sanieh at leur remettre tout surplus dont ils pourraient r4-sulter ddbiteure aprks remboursement de toot le peesif de la liquidation sur las bases oi-hant bdiqndee.

S’entendre lee contestants oondamner MX ddpens. *	. ^

Sous toutea lea plus a tuples reserves.

»

• *

II r&ulte de ce document qae, non settlement L.L. A.A. lee Princes et Prboesses ns contestant en auoune fe$on la oonvention do 21 Jain 1898, oonsentie par le GonveoMBMnt Egyptian et les effets de oette oonvention, maie qu’ils en reoonnaiesent la fegalitd pub-qu’ils se bornent en leur assignation k requdrir l’attrihnticn de “ toot le snrplos da prix de

II	vente des biens Delra aprks remboursement " de la dette gdndrale dale Daira Sanieh et " aprfes remboursement de toutas sornmes pon-“ vant 6tre does an Gouvemement Egyptian “ et aprks defalcation de toutea sommee rave* 11 nant k la Daira Sanieh Company limited par 11 suite d’engagement pris a son profit se vue “ de la liquidation des dits biens at enfin aprks “ remboursement de tons finds de tonti nature “ inhdrents k la gestion des dits biens par le “ Daira Sanieh de 8. A le Kb&tim”

Dbe lore rien de oe qui ravient k la Daira Sanieh Coy. Ld. on kses aotionnafree n’est r4olam4 et par suite aussi les aotionnairas qai ne oourent aaoun risque, n’aaroat k sahir auoan retard poor la liquidation de lean in-ferfits da ohef de oette reclamation judbiaiie, qai ne, ports exolasivement qae sar la part revenant an Gouvemement Egyptian.	#

. Poor aohever d’5olairer la situation qu’a eivisagde notre nnmdro da 28 aofit dernier, il n’est pas hors de propos de rappelet qu’un arrangement est intervenn les 2S et 25 janvier 1888 antra las membres de la fiynille Khidi-viale qui se portent aojoard’dni demandeers et le Gouvemement Bgyptien.

Le d5oret Khedivial da 80 avril 1888 a ap-prouvd oet arrangement xdont l’art 10 est einsi

OODCl :

Moyennant le present iohange, Lears Aites-■68 d4olarent formellement se ddsistar dal aotions par eux btroduitee oontre le Goaver-nement, renoncer k toutes rdoUmetioos qael-oonquee, d^olarent en outre, en an mot qae le Gouvernemont est entierement et dffinitivemenl liter* vit d-ris deux k cejour, tarn qu’il puisse y avoir reclamation k soulever pour quetque cause et tous quelque pretexts que ce soit, let prfsentes constituant un reglement de oompUs difinitxf.

Nous ne voolons pas oommenter.

Eofin l’on rapporte qae parmi les premiers aoheteurs de la Daira Sanieh Oy. Ltd. figure S.A. le Priuoe Ibrahim Helmy agismnt poor se m&re SA. la Pri cewe Veuve da Khldife Ismail.

On poarrait dono aoheter la ohoee dont on serait prltendnment proprfetaize 1 11
THEATRE ALHAMBRA.
La representation donnie hier soir k 1 A-lbambra au profit- des viotimes desetremhle-meats de terra de la Calabre a obtenu an grand snooks. Le Baron B. Aoton, oonsnl d’ltahe, y asaistajt entourd de tout le personnel de son oon8ulat; et la salle ktait comble.

La pifcoe ohoisie ktait "Come le foglie”. M. Maggi, l’exoellent artiste que nous avons en l'oooasion d’applandir tant de fois a Hi remar qn able dans le r5le de Massimo Bosani, ainaiqne Mme Dalla Gaardia dans oelni de Nenele oh elle a fait preuve de beauooup d’es-prit et d’un grand talent Les antras person-cages ont kgalement fort bien.

En Somme la representation a dfe tout k fait reusrie soit oomme ex5oution soit, oe qai est mien x encore, oomme r4«alUt ploumaire. Int Alexandrine ont montfe dans c®**®®**”®™ leur genlrosite ’traditionnelle so free aes grandee bfortunes. ^

I* pre-M ^amndripe •»Wt«n dawk da remermer ton. <»«I”

dan. l-orgMi-hon de oottnroirta da UMfcn-samoe, notammeot les impvnnenes J. Delia Bocoa et Penasson (A. V. Horn, saeeemenr) qai ont bien vonla found? k title graaieax tons lea imprimis: les Khmiries la Sehnler, Peochioli & Maronlis, et M. Oateo qnise tout nhargks de la Tents des bBlete. et la maison Llsndre Camilleri & Oa qui s'nt ehnigd de l’affiohage gratuit.
Madame Veuve Axis G. Mabardi et sss infants, les parents et allfcs, la Maison Stein-maun, Mabardi & Co., point leurs amis et oonnaissances de Men voulotr assiiter aux ohskquMde leur regsettlfixisGsoRoaiMMMDi dlodak k Mammem (Setose) to 6 ouwnnt Le oonvoi fankhre partim dt Tlgta DskkenA Itohbeil,tomermeil HMMmj k41 demto de Tij