THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, WEDNESDAY SEPTEMBER 20, 1905.
MOROCCAN CONFERENCE.
ARE RELATIONS STRAINED?
GERMANY AND MOGADOR.
Paris, September 19.

The negotiations on the subject of Morocco are beginning to excite uneasiness. It is stated that Germany’s pretentions are growing, in-cluding even the port of Mogador. (Reuter)

Berlin, September 19.

The "Koelnische Zeitung” denies that Germany is claiming Mogador or any other Moorish port. It declares that the interruption of the negotiations since Saturday is due to the absence of M. Rouvier.	(Reuter)
LOCAL AND GENERAL
The Brindisi Mail will be delivered at the G. P. 0., Alexandria, at 9.30 p m.
The Plague.—Yesterday’s plague bulletin shows a clean sheet, no cases having been notified.
Seizure of Gunpowder.—The coastguards have seized 174 okeg of gunpowder in the desert near Mariout
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Esbekieh quarter of Cairo during to morrow night and at dawn of the 22nd inst. will be poisoned by the police.
THE BAKU INSURGENTS.
RIOTING UNABATED.

Baku, September 19.

Murders, pillage, and incendiarism continue. Eleven derricks in the Viceroy’s oilfield, hitherto efficiently protected, were burned yesterday. The insurgents are obstructing and attacking the trains in the Tiflis district. (R.)
Tiflis, September 19.

Pillaging continues in the Baku region. (H.)
THE PEACE OF THE WORLD.
The Giraffe for the Sultan. - The Giraffe which was presented to H. H. the Khedive by Sir Roginald Wingate Pasha, has been sent to Constantinople as a gift to the Sultan, by the Khedive’s orders.
The El Rouei Affair. — We learn that Kamel Effendi Henain, the member of the secret police force who was shot in the recent affray at El Rousi died on Monday from the wounds which he received.
Suez Canal.—17 vessels passed through the Canal on the 16th and 17th inst., 11 of which were British, 2 German, 3 French, 1 Turkish. The receipts for the two days were frs.535,338.24, making the total from the 1st inst. -, fra. 4,726,833.64.
THE TSAR’S SCHEMES.

St. Petersburg, September 19.

The Tsar proposes to invite the Powers to a second Hague Conference.

President Roosevelt deferring to the idea of the Tsar, agreed that it is better that the initiative should come from the originator of the first conference.	(Reuter)
RUSSIAN ELECTIONS.
Tram Accident.—A native farmer, Raheen Said by name, in attempting to dismount from a tramcar at the wrong side fell and one of the wheels passed over his left foot, which was badly crushed. The man was removed to hospital, where he will have to make a lengthy stay.
POPULATION INDIFFERENT.

St. Petersburg, September 19. The greater part of the population of Russia is indifferent as to the approaching elections. Only a small proportion is taking up the franchise, as the people are dissatisfied with the inequitable representation of the cities.

(Reuter)
SPINNERS AND OPERATIVES.
Theft on a Steamer —On the arrival of the Khedivial Mail S.S. Prince Abbas from Turkey yesterday, a number of boatmen, porters, hotel runners and others rushed on board, while Europeans wishing to meet friends had to wait. M. Politi, a well-known resident, was caught in the crowd, and emerged without a gold watch and chain with gold eagle attached, and a silver cigarette case. In spite of the offer of £10 reward, no trace has been found of the stolen articles.
CONFERENCE BEING ARRANGED.

Manchester, September. 19.

Arrangements are proceeding satisfactorily for an early conference of Master Spinners and Operatives to formulate a mutual agreement for the automatic regulation of wages accord-ing to the recent settlement.	(Reuter)
Boy Found Buried in a Cotton Field.— Our Santa correspondent writes:—The body of the son of Sheikh Shahata Mansonr of Shou-brabola, near Santa, has been found buried in a cotton field. The lad, who was only twelve years of age, had been missing from his home for three days, and the grief of the parents, at finding that the child has been the victim of foul play, is great. The police are making every effort to find some trace of the criminal, but up to the present they have met with no success.
SCANDINAVIAN CONFERENCE.
PRINCIPAL POINTS AGREED.

Stockholm, September 19. The Scandinavian Conference has agreed upon the principal points.	(Havas)
GARRULOUS M. WITTE.
Paris, September 19.

M. Witte says that Japan renounced the indemnity on the threat of Mr. Roosevelt to withdraw the support of the United States.

(Havas)
M. WITTE'S MOVEMENTS.
Cherbourg, September 19. M. Witte has landed here He will proceed to Paris and Brussels, and will not return to Russia until November.	(Reuter)
BARON KAMURA CONVALESCENT.
New York, September 19. Baron Kamura is convalescent. (Reuter
FRESH SHOCKS IN CALABRIA.
Catanzaro, September 19. There were sharp shocks of earthquake in Calabria yesterday. Further damage was done. 	(Reuter
M. LOUBET.
Paris, September 19.

M. Loubet has accepted the invitation to go to Lisbon.	(Havas)
S.S. JOHN GRAFTON.
Stockholm, September 19. The crew of the John Grafton has landed from» two boats on the Swedish coast. (Reuter)
The Ibrahimieh Casino.—The performance at the variety theatre of the Casino, lbrahimieh, on Monday was noted for the début of M. Gaspard and Mlle. Néva, who sustained the reputation which they have brought with them from other countries. These artistes sing duets of a light vein in an attractive manner, and introduce a good deal of dancing, of which art both are good exponents. Mlle Néva has a pleasing voice, and is a very sprightly dancer, and M. Gaspard is an excellent humourist. The items provided by these duettists, added to the rest of the programme, constitute a good all-round evening’s entertainment.
Italian National Fete.—To-day being the anniversary of the entry of the royal troops into Rome the Italian communities of Cairo and Alexandria will celebrate the occasion this evening at the various places where special entertainments are to be given. In Alexandria the chief event will be the grand fête at the Alhambra theatre, consisting of short plays, a firework display, and a vocal and instrumental concert, and we feel sure that the knowledge that the proceeds will help to swell the relief fund for the Calabrian sufferers will attract even larger crowds than is usual on these anniversaries.
British Chamber of Commerce.—We would draw the attention of manufacturers and merchants to the work of the British Chamber of Commerce of Egypt, which was formed in 1896 with the sole object of assisting British trade in this country. The services of the Chamber are always at the disposal of any member desiring information on trade matters generally, including the question of appointing suitable agents. As no fee is charged for such advice, it is obviously in the interests of all British traders here to become members, especially when it is remembered that the annual subscription is merely the nominal one of £1. The latter payment also includes a copy of the monthly Journal issued by the Chamber. Home enquirers can obtain farther particulars from our London office, 36, New Broad-street, which acts as agents to the Chamber.

AMERICAN

REFRIGERATORS £4 to £20—DESKS, £5 to £25.

TYPEWRITERS £6 to £20.

SEWING MACHINES £5 TO £15.

THE AMERICAN MANUFACTURERS AGENCY

y, OLD BOURSE-STREET, SUBSOCK BUILDINGS, ALEXANDRIA.
THE SUCRERIES.
THE CONCORDAT PREVENTIF.

The application of the Sucreries and Raffinerie d’Egypte to be allowed the benefit of the concordat ’préventif came before the Commercial Chamber of the Cairo Mixed Court yesterday morning. The court was naturally full, the Cairo Bar and Press being well represented. The Court was composed of Mr. Somerville Tuck, presiding Judge, Messrs. Rassim Bey, Boustros, Montan, and Coghlan, Judges, M. Beer and Hussein Effendi Gallal, assessing Judges, Maher Bay, substitute, and M. Zigliara, greffier. After eight unimportant bankruptcy oases had been disposed of, Maître Carton de Wiart rose to plead that the Sucreries Company should be allowed the benefit of the concordat préventif. After recounting the origin of the company and describing its development, he pointed out that the feeling of the creditors was all in favour of the granting of the concordat as the beet solation for themselves and for the company. He cited numerous authorities in support of his contention that a joint-stock company can demand the application of the concordat and that its directors are at fall liberty to state the balance without calling any general meeting of shareholders. As to the question whether the company was in debt, all depended on the question whether it was to be held responsible for the agreements entered into by the late M. Cronier in its name. If so, it was in debt without question, but not otherwise.

Then came the question of the good faith of the directors. There was no reason to doubt it, for they, like the rest of the world had entire confidence in the agreement made by the firm Henri Say to guarantee the sums for bills discounted. In previous balance sheets the bills accepted by the company were balanced by the say guarantees and these balance sheets had been unanimously approved by the shareholders. Under these circumstances the conduct of the directors could not be impugned.

Turning to the interests involved, the speaker called the attention of the court to the disastrous results that would follow a declaration of bankruptcy. The agricultural population of a large tract of Upper Egypt, and the employé of the company would suffer terribly and their losses would react most injuriously opon the general prosperity of Egypt.

Should the directors be found to have acted in a manner unauthorised by the statutes of the company, proceedings might be taken against them in, the future, bat this was not a question for the moment. A provisional arrangement was required in the interests both of the company and its creditors. The names of Sir Elwin Palmer, Harari Pasha and M. Debourg, the proposed administrator under the concordat, were a good guarantee of a successful solution.

The speech ended a few minutes before 11 a.m. and Maher Bey rose to speak on behalf of the court. He was also in favour of the application of the concordat, but reserved the right, after the examination of the company's books and the expert’s report thereon, to demand that the company should be wound up and its directors—if necessary—prosecuted. The court then retired to deliberate, leaving the audience to discuss the situation and to congratulate Maître Carton de Wiart on his admirable speech. At 12.55 a.m. the court returned and the judgment was read granting the concordat Preventif. It ran as follows :

“ Le ministère public entendu, nomme M. Tuck, président de la Chambre, jage commissaire à l’effet de procéder aux opérations édictées par la loi en conformité des dispositions de l’article206 (nouveaucode), dépens réservés; ordonne à la Société des Sucreries d'avoir dans les huit jours du prononcé du présent jugement à déposer au greffe ses livres et pièces comptables. "

The general impression in the audience was one of unalloyed satisfaction. It was felt on all sides' that the granting of the concordat was the only possible solution of the present crisis that would satisfy creditors and shareholders and stave off a disastrous crash. Maître Helou who appeared as counsel for a group of Alexandrian shareholders declined to speak, after the remarks made by Maher Bey with whom he entirely agreed, and the bar was obviously under the impression that the only course that could reconcile a number of conflicting individual interests had been followed by the court.
(By Telephone).

To-day by the order of Judge Somerville Tuck the Sucreries were authorised to continue their business, bat under the control of Sir E Palmer, Harari Pasha and M. Eugène Debourg. The meeting of creditors will take place on October 4 at 10 a.m. under the presidency of Judge Took, at the Mixed Tribunals, Cairo.
DAILY WEAHTER EFFORT
ALEXANDRIA.
Direction of Wind....
N.E.
Htote of Fee ...... .	.......... ..	^	„ . Almost ctlxa

r»r*r» (Ytx, Ter p.It t!» rl»£r.... .. » .. . «o.o

4 Irrt»» J M'r. ¿c. ec. 	....	 19.1

.rtfre , Jt»Ki»r ».......	......... rao

».c:. I Unfall.. 			 —
THE AGRICULTURAL SHOW.
(From our Correspondent.)

Fayoum, Sunday.

The agricultural show, which came to an end yesterday, has been a great success. and will long remain a red letter event in the annals of Medinet el Fayoum's history. Both visitors and those who were exhibiting, expressed themselves as greatly pleased with the arrangements which were made and the organising committee is to be highly congratulated upon the success with which their efforts have met.

Daring the three days of the exhibition the whole town was "en fête”, and bands of music were greatly in evidence. There were also two fashionable native weddings, which added to the festivities, especially that of Gofar Pasha, son of the ex-Governor of the Sudan.

The Princes visited the house of Tobla Bay, a member of the Legislative Council, and they took afternoon tea with Khalid Bey yesterday.

Amongst the most prominent visitors to the show on Saturday I might mention Mr. Wilson, of the Ministry of the Interior, Tadrous Bey, proprietor of the “Misr” and Abrahim Bey Ramsi, proprietor of the "Tamadou”.

THE NATIVE TRIBUNALS.

Mezler Bey, president of the Beni Souef tribunals, paid a visit of inspection to Medinet el Fayoum last weekend, I understand, expressed himself as very pleased at the work which is being done, and with the general condition of the tribunals.
NOTES FROM FAY0ÜM.
NOTES FROM SUAKIN.
DEATH OF GEORGE MACDONALD.
London, September 19.

The writer George Macdonald, LL.D. is dead.	(Reuter)

George Macdonald, the celebrated poet and author has passed away at the ripe age of 81. Of late years his name has not been very prominent in the literary world, and living abroad, he only paid annual visits to England. Daring the latter half of the last century he was, however, a power in the land, and such books of his as the "Annals of a Quiet Neighbourhood,” “Guild Court,” “Robert Falconer,” and others were highly appreciated, especially by those in sympathy with his advanced theological views. As a poet he ranked high in the public estimation, and his occasional appearances in the pulpit always drew large congregations.

Dr Macdonald was born at Huntly, Aberdeenshire, in 1824, and was educated at the parish school there, and at King’s College and University, Aberdeen. After taking his degree he became a student for the ministry at the Independent College, Highbury, London, and was for a short time an Independent minister, bat soon retired, became a lay member of the Church of England, and settled in London to pursue a literary career. His first work was "Within and Without, a Dramatic Poem,” 1856 ; followed by "Poems,” 1857 ; "Phantasies, a Faerie Romance,” 1858; “David Elginbrod,” 1862; "Adela Cathcart,” 1864; •The Portent, a Story of Second Sight,” 1864 ; “Alec Forbes of Howglen,” 1865 ; "Annals of a Quiet Neighbourhood,” 1866; “Guild Court,” 1865; The Disciple and other Poems,” 1868 ; "The Seaboard Parish,” 1868 ; "Robert Falconer,”1868; "Wilfrid Cumbermede,” 1871; 'The Vicar's Daughter,” "Malcolm,” 1874; "St. George and St. Michael” 1875; "Thomas Wingfield, Curate,” 1876 ; "The Marquis of Lossie,” 1877. "Sir Gibbie,” 1879; "The Diary of an Old Soul ”1880; "Castle Warlock,” 1882; "Weigh-ed and Wanting,” 1882 ; "The wise woman,” 1888; "There and Baok,” 1891; "Heather and Snow,” 1893 ; "Lilith,” 1895 ; "Salted with Fire,” 1897; "Rampolli,” 1897. Besides these Dr. Macdonald has written books for the young : "Dealings with the Fairies,'' 1867 ; Ranald Bannerman’s Boyhood,” 1869 ; "The Princess and the Goblin,” 1871 ; “At the Back of the North Wind,” 1870 ; and others. He is also the author of "Unspoken Sermons,” 1866 ; and a treatise on the "Miracles of our Lord,” 1870. In 1877 he received a Civil List pension of £100, in consideration of his contributions to literature. Among his well-known works should be mentioned. "The Gifts of the Child Christ,” and other poems, 2 vols., 1882 ; and "The Princess and Cardie,” a fairy romance, 1882.

THE LATE M. MABARDI.
The body of the late M. Aziz Georges Ms-bardi, the well-known partner of the firm Steinmann, Mabardi and Co., who died at Mammern, Switzerland, arrived at Alexandria this morning. The funeral will take place this afternoon, starting from the Debbane Church at half past four.
ARISTON AERATED WATERS

Guaranteed Distilled.
ALEXANDRIA !

!.. R-u d«lwTa»te.
i CAI ROI »watt» Um (ntnn •«. Tetto 1 XfcMte fetal Kaasal-lW
Tb» weather «cotton»» fin» ixd the degree of humidity 1» rather bekw normal. The barometer tM en upward CaflW alight at
CARLTON HOTEL,

MUCHI» (MV MuaaM.)

BAMLEB'B FASHIONABLE HOTÍL patbonisxd by thx «arra, mil Pautan Mi P.T. S* »Aar.

«atar
RAILWAY NOTES.

(From our Correspondent).

Suakin, September 13.

Mr. Urquhart, bridge contractor for the Suakin-Atbara line arrived by the Khedivial Mail S S. Dakahlieh and brought with him a number of workmen to replace those whose contracts have expired. Kaimakam Longfield Bey, RE, left for Railhaed on the 11th inst., and will meet Kaimakam Midwinter Bey, RE, and .discuss with him several matters, including the question of what is to be done with the surplus material which remains over from that brought out for the construction of the Suakin-Atbara line. Bim-bashi Sowerby, RE, has taken over Longfield Bey’s work during the latter’s absence.

The British steamer Shahristan arrived here on the 8rd inst. with a consignment of steel sleepers and material for the bridges. She left for India yesterday.
RETURN OF OFFICIALS.

A number of Government officials arrived here by the Khedivial Mail S.S. Dakahlieh from Suez on the 10th inst Many of the officials’ wives, who have been spending the summer at home also returned by the same boat
THE NEW ZIFTA BRIDGE.
The work of erecting the new railway bridge at Zifta will shortly be commenced, a large quantity of material having recently arrived from France. This bridge is to be constructed by Messrs. Dayde and Pillé who are one of the three firms whose designs for the Rodah bridges were finally selected, out of a large number that were sent in and submitted to the Ministry of Public Works for final decision, with the resalt as our readers are aware, that the tender of Messrs. Sir William Arrol and Co. was accepted. The new bridge will be to the north of Zifta, between that town and the barrage, and will serve for the new line from Tantah to Zagazig. When this bridge is completed, next year, the same firm will commence the construction of three others, one on the Damietta branch of the Nile, and the other two on the Tewfikieh and Menoufieh canals respectively.
THE COMING TOURIST SEASON.
Messrs. Thos. Cook & Son have just issued their annual illustrated handbook for the Nile services for the coming winter, which will be practically the same as those of last season. Their steamers will begin to ran between Cairo and the First Cataract on the 3rd November and continue until the 23rd of March, with later connecting steamers between the First and Second Cataracts. A new feature, to which we call attention, is the arrangement of combined bookings by Messrs. Cook’s steamer and the Egyptian and Sudan Railways, enabling tourists with only limited time at their disposal to make their visits to Upper Egypt and the Sudan more rapidly than can be done by using the steamers only. Combined tickets are issued as far as Gondokoro, a Uganda, to which there is a Government steamer service once a month from Khartoum by up-to-date boats fitted with electric light, hot and cold baths, etc.

Messrs. Cook will charge specially reduced rates for residents in Egypt daring November and December.
THREATENED STRIKE.
We are informed that a number of the workmen employed at the Cotton Pressing Mills submitted a petition to the acting Commandant of Police yesterday, in which they complained that unjust deductions from their pay had been made by certain foremen, and stated their intention of going on strike unless justice was done. The acting Commandant promised to investigate the case.
LAND BANK OF EGYPT.
The Committee of the London Stock Exchange has ordered the following security to be quoted in the official list :—

Land Bank of Egypt—Bearer Warrants for 95,000 Ordinary Shares of £5 each fully paid, Nos. 1 to 95,000.
SAN STEFANO CASINO.
The following is the programme of music to be performed to-morrow afternoon at San Stefan Casino.

Marche des Joyeux Muscadius-Diodet

Valse -Lune de Miol -Waldteufeul.

Ouverture—Lo Domino Noir—Auber.

Mennet--N. 1 op 14—Paderewaki

Fantaisie—Lohengrin—Wagner.

Transcription« Humoristuques d'une chanson populaire » Allemande dans le style dea différent maltres classic
CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES.
THE KHEDIVE'S ARRIVAL
(From our Correspondent).

Constantinople, September 12.

As the telegraphic agencies have doubtless informed you, H.H. the Khedive arrived here last Saturday by the Orient Express.

At the Sirkeje station Ibrahim Pasha, grand master of ceremonies, representing the Sultan, H H. Field-Marshal Prince Mohamad Ali Pasha, brother of H H. the Khedive, General Husni Pasha, Captain Hassan Bey, A.D.C. to the Saltan, Mahmoud Bhukri Bey, and numerous other officials were waiting to greet the distinguished visitor. Immediately after leaving the train the Khedive entered a state carriage, accompanied by Ibrahim Pasha, and, followed by two other carriages, in the first of which were Ahmed Pasha Zeki and General Husni Pasha, while Izzet Bey followed in the seoond, drove to the Yildiz Kiosk with a mounted escort. On his arrival the Khedive was most warmly received by the Saltan and remained some time in conversation with him. He then left for Bebek, where he visited his mother, Princess Emina Hanem, and afterwards left for Chiboukli in the launch Rehber, accompanied  by his physician and his chief Imam, Sheikh Osman Effendi.

Izzet Bey and the thief eunuch, Almas Aga, met his Highness at Mustafa-Pasha station on the Turkish frontier.

In the evening the Khedive received the visits of the first dragomans of the Powers represented at Constantinople, and begged them to transmit his salutations to their respective ambassadors. Yesterday evening he was present at a grand dinner given in his honor by the Saltan at Yildis.
SPORT AND PLAY.
CRICKET.
E.T.C. v. SGT. BURKE’S MILITARY XL

Sergeant Burke’s XI. won the toss and elect ed to bat They started none too well, losing two wickets for one ran. Pte. Sides and Sgt Burke, however, improved matters, till Pte. Sides was bowled by McLean, then the end soon came. For the E T.C. Messrs. Stacey end Henley took the score from 9 for one wioket to 105, at which point Henley was bowled, and Stacey leaving soon after made way for Byrne and Cheesman, who fairly collared the bowling and quickly added nearly 100 ran. Scores Sgt. Burkes xl

Pte. Sides b. McLean	 4|

Cpl. New c. Henley b. Thurston		0

Cpl. Morrison o. Scarth b. Thurston...	0

Sgt Burke a Soarth th. MoLean ...	94

Cpl. Bargees Lb.w. b. MoLean 	 0

Gr. Pike o. and b. Byrne 	 l

Qms. Saunders h. Byrne 	 4

Pte. Crutoh b. Byrne 	 0

Pte. Taylor not ont 	   1

Pte. Cowie o. Henley b. MoLean		9

Gr. Fryer b. Byrne 	 ... o

Extras 	 6
Total...
87
Bowling
Overs Maidens Runs Wickets
Mr. Thurston	4	0	27	2

„	Blythman	8	0	24	0

..	Byrne	9.1	8	24	4

it	B. McLean	7	2	12	4

E T. 0.

C. B. Staoey b. Taylor	 68

P. R Harrison b. Barke ... ...	0

R G.	Henley	b. Cratch 	 85

R. C.	VoLean	o. Sides b. Cratoh		4

G.	N. Chessman not ont 	 88

P.'J. Byrne not -nnt 	 6a

C. F. Steele

H.	F. Tharitou

M. Blythman Did not bat C. S.	Soarth

G. B.	Harvey

Extras 	 18
Total for 4 wickets...
991
Bowling
Overs Maidens Rons Wickets
Sgt Barke	10	8	34	1

Pte. Sides	11	2	52	0

Cpl. Morrison	4	0	20	0

Pte. Cowie	7	1	41	0

Pte. Cratoh	7	0	29	2

Pte. Teylor	9	1	27	i
PERSONAL AND SOCIAL
Mukhtar Pasha El Ghazi, Ottoman High Commissioner, will leave the Continent for Egypt on October 4.

Ismail Pasha Sabri left Alexandria for Cairo yesterday afternoon.

Kotta Bey. Secretary to the Council of Ministers, has arrived from Europe.
Intermezza--Ids Letosblume--Lincke
STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
M. Maximoff, Diplomatic Agent and Consul general for Russia arrived at Alexandria from Cairo yesterday afternoon.
The Khedivial Mail S.S. Prince Abbas will leave Alexandria to-morrow at 2 p.m., a special mail service for Constantinople direct, with passengers and general cargo.
Shawky Bey, the Egyptian poet laureate, arrived at Alexandria yesterday from Constantinople.
Maitre Mohamad Bey Hafis Ramadan has been appointed Penal Code teacher at the Cairo Poli