THE EGYPTIAN  GAZETTE, MOND AY, SEPTEMBER 18,1905.

THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE.
SUBSCRIPTIONS.—Alexandria, Cairo, and the Interior of Egypt (including delivery in Alexandria or postage to subscriber's address) P.T. 2311/2 per annum, P.T. 116 for months, P.T. 80 for three months. To other countries in the Postal Union P.T. 278 (£2.16s.) per annum. Six months P.T. 1361/2 (£1.8s.), three months P.T. 95 (0.19s.)

N.B.— Subscriptions commence from the 1st or 16th of any month.

ADVERTISEMENTS. - P.T. 4 per line. Mi-nimum charge P.T. 20. Births, Marriages, or Deaths, not exceeding three lines, P.T. 20 Every additional line P.T. 10. Notices in news column P.T. 20 per line. Contracts entered into for standing advertisements.

SUBSCRIPTIONS and ADVERTISEMENTS are due in advance. P. O. Orders and Cheques to be made payable to the Editor and Manager,Rowland Suelling, Alexandria.

London Offices : 36, New Broad-street, E.C.

THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE can be obtained in London at our office, 86, New Broad Street, E.C., and also at Messrs. May & Williams, 160, Piccadilly, W.
it would be doomed to failure, and its prohibi tion in public offices and conveyances is, for the present, the only practicable limitation of vice —for a habit dangerous to the safety of the public health is a vice—at which the State can aim. But public opinion can be educated, and a new generation may yet be trained to regard with disgust what passed unnoticed among its ancestors, and we urge the leaders of the present movement against the disease to show no discouragement if their ideas are slow in finding favor with the people. Edu-cation is really the best remedy for disease, and it is on the gradual spread of education among the masses, especially in the great cities, that our sanitary reformers must rely.
CRUELTY TO ANIMALS.

"Man’s inhumanity to man” is too frequently accompanied by cruelty to animals, and no claims on humanity are greater than those advanced by the societies established for the purpose of repressing that cruelty, and lessening its results on the suffering victims. Com-plaints on the parts of visitors daring the winter season have been so frequent of late years that we would urge upon all who can do so, the necessity of exerting any influence, however slight, in the direction of securing better treatment, not only of horses, mules, and donkeys, or other animals which the so-cieties more especially protect, but of dogs, cats and birds, the latter more especially, in view of the scenes enacted before the eyes of tourists during their trips on the Nile, for the purpose of extorting money from the sympathetic. Two months will elapse before the tourist influx commences ; it promises to be greater than ever this year, and in proportion to the increase of visitors, will be the number of animals required for their use, and the scope for the practice of cruelty. If in the meantime some efforts can be made, individual and collective, to instruct the native, give him a few lessons on kindness to animals, or, if necessary, set before and the probability of punishment for wanton cruelty, a great step will have been taken towards in some measure reducing the shocking cruelty at present so rife, and so little thought of.

There is fine scope in a country like Egypt for the introduction of the system inaugurated in England many years ago by that eminent philanthropist, Lord Shaftesbury. It is not too much to say that by his efforts in the East End of London, his lordship completely altered the treatment of the London donkey by the costermonger. Instead of treating him as a mere beast of harden, out of which the last ounce should be taken in the way of work, Lord Shaftesbury taught the lesson of kind ness, and by offering prises for the best-kept animals, induced a spirit of emulation among the costers that soon bore fruit in well-fed, well-groomed, and willing animals. The effect of this philanthropic work did not pass away with the man to which it owed its inception, and to this day the results of his life work may be seen by any one acquainted with the London costermonger and his ways. If we were to suggest what we think affords the best opening individual effort for ill-used animals, we should say that there is much to be done towards inducing better treatment of mules. One has only to watch for a short time the painful struggles of the poor animals in two-wheeled carts, laden with building material, dragging their loads, through deep sands, and straining their utmost to bring them to their destinations, to see how these must tell upon the life of the animals. "The merciful man is merciful to his beast” and it is this lesson that wants enforcing, in and out of season, and at any and every opportunity.
THE “EGYPTIAN GAZETTE" IS PRINTED ON PAPER MANUFACTURED AND SUPPLIED BY THE LONDON PAPER MILLS Co„ LIMITED (SALES OFFICE : 27, CANNON STREET, EC.)
The Egyptian Gazette

An English Daily Newspaper, Established 1880,

Editor and Manager : R Snelling. Price: One Plastre Tariff.
MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 18, 1905.
TUBERCULOSIS IN EGYPT.

We should like to call the attention of our readers to the excellent work now being carried on by the Egyptian Anti-Tuberculosis League. Egypt, which might have been described as one of the most “immune” countries in the world till a few years ago, is undoubtedly beginning to suffer from an increase of phthisis and other tu-bercular diseases, which, in too many oases, appear to have been imported by Europeans them selves in search of health. The change of habits and mode of life by a sectionof the native popula-tion is also believed by some authorities to be a cause of the greater prevalence of phthisis among the Arabs, and the risk that this and kindred diseases may become firmly established in the country is accentuated by the extraordinary ignorance of most of the native and of part of the European population in all matters connected with hygiene, The practice of spitting broadcast, which is so unpleasantly frequent in Egypt is fraught with great danger to the public in cases where a consumptive cannot relinquish the habit, and it is most that public opinion here should support the crusade undertaken by doctors against this pernicious practice on the part of persons suffering from phthisis. Government can do little to combat a widespread custom, however contrary it may be to the rules of health or good taste.  An attempt to enforce a law against
Calendar of Coming Events.

Alexandria.

September.

Mon. 18 Mex. Prinea’s Restaurant das Bains Roumanian orchestra, every after-noon. Sundays, morning.

Windsor Hotel Orchestra. 6 to 11.30 p.m. every day.

Alhambra. — Italian company. — Gome le Foglie. 9.15 p.m.

Grown Casino. Ibrahimieh. 9.30 p.m.
October. Sat 7
Alex. Swimming Sports.
Club. Aquatic
CAIRO.

September.

Mon. 18 Esbekieh Theatre. French Operetta. Company. 9.15 p.m.

Theatre dee Nouveautea. 9.30 p m. Alcazar Parision. 9.30 p.m.

Tues. 19 Esbekieh Gardens. Pertormanca by British Military Band. 9 to 11 p.m. Fri. 22 Esbekieh Gardens. Performance by British Military Band. 9 to 11 p m.
DAILY WEATHER REPORT

OBSERVATION BY SURVEY DEPARTMENT ALEXANDRIA

JlncUoa ot wind				North

STof^i " "	•—Si£

issa ita 	s.,°

^isaa»	:—-°

huhh

There hM been no change la the weather eince BatanUy. The barometer which hu boen v*r/ «toady of lata baa (alien slightly «thin morning.

OTHMB STATIONB.

For the M boon ending ( a-m. Totarday

Max.	Min.	Max.	Mia.

Sr men.	tamp.	tamp.	Krtnon.	lamp,	tie»

ESS la th.	In the in th-

■hade,	abed., 	 «bade.	aW-

'an Bold.		>3	M	Haro we.........	18	>8

		U	U	Berber		41	»	'

¿fBlelotmo.. 84 U doama «...	87	ti

—■	M	88	Wed Memae..	.'8	13

Wady Haifa..	M	ft

roaaati station«.

B^nen.	iHrom. | Wind. I Tmnp. >-ta at

rrtami. M 	  *«J>	Oalm	j	*8	|	Oalm

«aim.		   783.8	! Very	:	»	j	Blight

itladU	 «1»	Very	18	,	Blight

.thee^	..	 788.4 Oalm 81 Oalm

amaaatl				 784.1 Alm-iat 81 Vary

calm 1	I alight

FHA8B8 or THE MOON	THE «UK.

Biaaamm. Bata pj*.

Sept 6	riiat Quarter	6. 9	mm.	8M	AU

„	18	Fall Moon	8.10	pjn.	A88	A 4

..	81	beat Quarter	8.11	ajn.	Att	1.83

18	New Moon	A 0	-	A87	8.48
EGYPTIAN DELTA LIGHT RAILWAYS; HELOUAN DISTRICT.

A special service of passenger trains will be run between Bab el Louk and Bassatine stations on the 8th October proxo on the occasion of the Jewish All Souls’ day. Cost of tickets :—

1st class 50 mill. — 2nd class 40 mill.—8rd class 20 mill. No single or half ticket will be issued, and children over 4 years pay full fare.—Trains will leave Bab el Louk every half hour from 5.15 a.m., until 8.40 Am.— Time tables are posted up at all stations of the Helouan Kailway.	26437 3-2

THE

ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK,

LIMITED.

LONDON, PARIS ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO MALTA, GIBRALTAR, TANT AH,

AND PORT SAID.

Subscribed Capital ₤

Paid up	At	600,000

BoaorveFnnd ... ...	At	600,000

The Anglo-Egyptian Bank. Limited, undertakes every description of banking business an the most favourable conditions.

Current accounts opened with commercial houses and private individuals in conformity with the custom of Bankers.

fixed depot!* for ona year certain received at * yai oant. per annum. Depoeit* at intaraat for abort«’ •rioda ara alto received at xatat to ba agreed ufou.

Lattar« of Credit for ths os« of traveOara arr tanad payable in all parte of tha World.

Approved bflls di «counted.

BO«, documentary involew, ate., collected. Draft« and talagraphle tranatea i*.u«d r*y ill« afl om tha World.

Foreign exchange bought and aold.

Advaaaas mads agon approved saenritlaa and gon^aottoo, eotton-aaod, mgax and other mer

Th« purehaM and nil of itoaka and aharat on tha London Stock Bx change; and on thr local and Oontinantal Bourne, undartak«n.

Owtemara can dcsocit their valuable*, bonds, •IS., for safe eortody in th« Banka fire-proof atrong-rooma, and tbs Bank wOl attend to tea aollaatlftn of tha ooapoiu and down bonds ao dapoalted as th«y iaU doa.

Annul tie«, pantion., ¿¡videndy, ate., ooUaeted Ail father partienlara and Itfloroaetiaa a an ba obteinad it application.

Tht offlotn and tlerks of tht Bank on pledged to attrtey m to tht tni< M«OM V twtomtrg	A M9f
THE EGYPTIAN  GAZETTE, MOND AY, SEPTEMBER 18,1905.
