THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 18 1905
SCANDINAVIAN CRISIS.

MEETING OF DELEGATES.

RUMOURED COMPROMISE

Stockholm, September 16. Sweden has demanded the dismantling of the forts on the Norwegian frontier. Norway refuses.	(Havas)

Stockholm, September 17. The Swedo-Norwegian delegates held three sittings yesterday. An official communiqué says that there is reason to hope that the negotiations will shortly reach a definite result.

(Later). The delegates met again to-day. It is understood that a compromise has arrived at. Great satisfaction and relief is felt in both capitals.	(Reuter)

Stockholm, September 17.

An official communication states that it is hoped that the Norwegian crisis will soon be brought to a positive result.	(Havas)

THE CALABRIAN EARTHQUAKE.

KING VICTOR RETURNS.

Rome, September 16.

King Victor Emmanuel has returned. (R.)

Rome, September 17.

,King Victor Emmanuel in an interview granted to the Premier said that he brought back with him a vision of horror and anguish, which no imagination could conceive, and no person could describe. He relies on the government and nation to help to redeem his promises to the sufferers.	(Reuter)

VOLCANIC ACTIVITY.

FREQUENT UNDULATORY SHOCKS.

Naples, September 16. Vesuvius is increasingly active with frequent undulatory shocks around the volcano. The activity of Stromboli is also very remarkable.

(Reuter)

RUSSIA AND AMERICA.

RETALIATORY DUTIES.

St. Petersburg, September 16. An Imperial Ukase abolishes the retaliatory duties on American products.	(Reuter)
THE CAUCASUS REVOLT.
PRINCE NAPOLEON ACTIVE.
A PROCLAMATION.
Baku, September 16.

The insurgents hero threaten to kill the workmen who are resuming work and to burn the works where there is any attempt to repair the damages. Firing took place on Thursday night in various districts and there were many skirmishes with considerable loss of life. (R.)
Body Recovered After Two Weeks.—The body of a European woman was recovered from the sea near the fort Kaid Bey yesterday. Examination proved that the woman would bo about 25 years of age, and the conclusion arrived at from the autopsy was that the body had remained two weeks in the water. The body is, as yet, unidentified, but the police are making every effort to find some clue which will lead to identification.
Tiflis, September 16.

The Viceroy of the Caucasus in a proclamation to the inhabitants points out the disastrous consequences of the subservive work of the secret societies by which the formerly flourishing trade at Baku has teen ruined. He urges the population to cooperate in the pacification of the district.	(Reuter)

Tiflis, September 16.

Prince Louis Napoleon who was appointed Governor General of the Caucasus has just arrived. He is already bringing to justice the police officials who ignored massacres. (R.)

St. Petersburg, September 16.

Part of an army corps at Kieff has been ordered to the Caucasus.	(Reuter)
REOIVAL OF NAPHTHA INDUSTRY.

St. Petersburg, September 17.

The Tsar has ordered the assembly of a representative conference, of which the Minister of Finance will be president, to consider what measures should be taken to revive the naphtha industry, and to take steps for the concentration of sufficient troops to guarantee order in the oilfields. (Reuter)
TWO MORE RISINGS.

Berlin, September 17 The governor of German East Africa reports rising in two more districts.	(Reuter)

CRETAN ADVANCED PARTY.
Canea, September 16.

The advanced party has forced several reforms to be adopted by the Chamber. (H.)
SOUTH WESTERN AFRICA.
HEREROS’ DESPERATE RESISTANCE

Cape Town, September 16.

The Hereros in South Western Africa con tinue to offer a skilful and desperate guerilla resistance to the Germans. Occasionally bands are routed, but the progress made towards pacification is of the slowest.	(Reuter)
FLOODS IN CAPE COLONY.
THOUSANDS OF ACRES RUINED.

Cape Town, September 16.

Severe floods following the drought in Cape Colony have caused great damage. They have destroyed the Irrigation works at Gamtoos River, ruining thousands of acres of cultivated land.	(Reuter)
RUSSIAN VOLUNTEER FLEET.
THE EAST ASIATIC SERVICE.

Odessa, September 16. The Volunteer Fleet is resuming the East-Asiatic service. A steamer is leaving here on Wednesday for Nagasaki and Vladivostok. Enormous quantities of goods are awaiting shipment to Siberia.	( Reuter)
THE TSAR’S CRUISE.
St. Petersburg, September 16.

It is reported that the Tsar and the Tsarina will embark on their yacht at Cronstadt to-day for a 3 or 4 days’ cruise.	(Reuter)
St. Petersburg, September 16. The Tsar has started for a cruise in the Finnish Archipelago.	(Reuter)
St. Petersburg, September 17. The Tsar and Tsarina have embarked on the Polar Star for a cruise in the Finland Archipelago.	(Havas)
BARON KAMURA BETTER.
New York, September 16, Baron Kamura's illness has taken a favor-able turn.	(Reuter)
ABATEMENT OP CHOLERA.
Berlin, September 16, The cholera in Prussia is rapidly abating.

(Reuter)
RUSSIAN REPRESENTATIVE COUNCIL.
Soldiers’ Club.— The final match in the billiard handicap for Warrant and N.C.Officers was played on Saturday last, and resulted in an easy win for Sergeant Crane, 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade (owing 40) who, playing in a confident manner, ran out a winner by 70 points. His opponent, Sergeant Bernet, 2nd Battalion Rifle Brigade (owing 50) was evidently not in his usual form, although giving occasional evidence of his skill, by breaks of 24,21 and twice 19, was unable to pull up to his opponent and eventually last by the number stated.

The Bubonic Plague.—There was only one case of plague notified in Egypt during last week, namely at Alexandria on the 14th inst Eight cures were effected, of which six at Alexandria, one at Damietta, and one at Assouan. Last Saturday five cases remained under treatment, all which are in hospital at Alexandria, and of these five only one is a native. Since January 1 there have been in all 256 cases as against 799 during the corresponding period last year. Yesterday’s bulletin reports one admission to hospital at Alexandria, a native groom from a stable at Gincinet.

An Infant Found Drowned.—The body of a little girl of two years of age has been found in the Mahmoudieh canal by the Karmous. The child, Zanouba bint Mohamed by name, had not been at her father’s house for two days before her body was discovered, and it is supposed that she fell into the canal whilst playing on the bank. The occurrence of such an accident to a child only two years of age can only be due to gross negligence on the part of the mother, or the person who should have looked after the child, and to all appearances, the parents must have been altogether indifferent as to its safety.

A New Geography.—We have received from Ahmed Effeudi Hafez, an official of the Alexandria post office, a small work entitled "A New Geography” which has been dedicated to Youssef Saba Pasha, director-general of the Egyptian post-offices. This text book is intended for the pupils of Egyptian Schools and has been compiled according to the recent syllabus drawn up by the Ministry of Public Works. It is written in a simple style which can readily be understood by any at all acquainted with the English language, and is illustrated. Much information is given regarding the chief commerce of the various oountries, and the populations are also numerically dealt with.
GERMAN EAST AFRICA.
THE LATE M. DE BRAZZA.

Paris, September 16.

The government has decided that M. de Brazza shall be buried in state. (Havas)
HOME SPORT.
London, September 16. Cricket. Yorkshire beat the rest of England by 65 runs.	(Reuter)
LOCAL AND GENERAL
Drowned in the Canal.—A native lad of but ten years of age was drowned whilst bathing in the Mahmoudieh Canal on Saturday.
The Prisons Department.—A farther grant of £15,000 has been accorded to the Prisons Department in view of the largely increased number of prisoners.
Sanitary Department.—Drs. Georges Dions tambani, Constantin Frangoulis, and Emile Selum Orfali have been authorised to practise their profession in Egypt.
PUBLIC INSTRUCTION.
SECONDARY EDUCATION.

The number of pupils presenting themselves for secondary education has been increasing so rapidly of late that it has been found necessary to provide farther accomodation. Two new secondary schools are to be built in the neighbourhood of Cairo to accommodate 400 pupils each, and the Government has granted suitable sites,one at Ghizeh and the other at Abbas-sieh. About this time last year the number of applicants for admittance was 430, whilst this year the applications already number nearly 550.

While in England lately Mr. Dunlop, the Secretary General, engaged an additional staff of 24 schoolmasters who are expec'ed out next week. Some of these gentlemen are to fill existing vacancies caused by transfer to other Government departments, and others are to be trained for the work of teaching in the native schools. Two schoolmistresses are arriving at the same time.

The new primary school now building at Benha is nearly completed and will be opened early in the new year.

STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
SPORT AND PLAY.
The M.M. mail boat, which left Marseilles on the 14th inst, passed the straits of Messina last Saturday and is due at Alexandria tomorrow.

The S.S. Sailor Prince left Malta on Saturday with passengers and general cargo, and is due to arrive at Alexandria on Wednesday.

    PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.

Among the arrivals by the Austrian Lloyd Semiramis this morning we noticed Khalil Pasha Hamada, Dr. Komonos Pasha, Mohamed Pasha Shoukry, Saad el Din Pasha and E.K. Corbet Bey.

Sir Charles Holled Smith, who celebrated his fifty ninth birthday on the 12th inst is a soldier with a magnificent record. Entering the 60th just forty years ago, Sir Charles first saw service during the Zola War, and later in the Boer War. In 1882 he was fighting in Egypt, and was present at Tel-el-Kebir and Kassassin. The Nile Expedition then claimed him, and be commanded a brigade at the battle i of Gamazieh. For a time Sir Charles was Governor-General of the Red Sea Littoral, and  acted as commandant at Suakin, whence he took an expedition to Forkar. Before going to South Africa in 1899, where he saw much service, Sir Charles was in Australia in com mand of the local forces of Victoria. He is a Pasha, with several Egyptian orders.
CRICKET.
A.C.C. v. 2nd ROYAL BERKSHIRE REGT.

This match, probably the last of the present season, was played on the A.C.C. ground Friday afternoon. The Regimental XI. won the toss and went in first, but started badly, losing two wickets in the first over. Captain Moore and Murphy made a good stand, both hitting very freely and putting on 42 runs for the fourth wicket, but after their dismissal Major Finch was the only batsman to give much trouble.

The A.C.C. on going in made a bad start, losing two wickets for nine runs, but J. G. Maclaren, who completed his 1,000 runs for the season amid considerable applause, helped Stacey to carry. the score to 51 and H. B. Carver and Stacey quickly made matters safe. Both hit very freely, Stacey scoring 14 fours in his 69, while Carver hit two fives and eight boundaries.

The Cricket club was "at home” in honor of the occasion during the match and the pavilion was crowded. Among those present were Mr. M. de C. Findlay, C.M.G., Mr. Rum bold, Mr. Mitchell Innes, Col. McCracken, Capt. Borton, the officers of the 2nd Royal Berks, Mr. and Mrs. Sydney Carver, and the Misses Carver, Mr. and Mrs. Macpherson Grant, Capt. and Mrs. Kelham, Mr. and Mrs. R. Moss, Mrs. Cave, Mrs. Herbert Carver, Mr. and Mrs. Logan, Mr. and Mrs. Briscoe, Mrs. Fraser, Mrs. Stafford Northcote, Mrs. Atkin, and many others whom we hare no space to mention. The two teams were photographed after the match and the photograph should be a very pleasant souvenir of the occasion. We should like to voice the satisfaction of all who were present at the really excellent arrangements made by the captain and committee of the club for the occasion.

Score and analysis.

Royal Berkshire Regiment.
Mr. A. P. Strange, c. Maclaren b. Graves

Loe-Corp. Morrison, b. Graves 	

Maj. Artbuthurst, b. Graves 	

Capt More, c. Maclaren b. Byrne	

Mr. P. Murphy, a R, Carver b. Graves

i Pte. Sides, ran oat 	

Loe.-Corp. New, b. Byrne 	

Capt Bingley, b. Maclean	

Maj. Finch, not out 	

Mr. J. R. Robertson, b. H. B. Carver... Pte. Crutch, o. & b. EL B. Carver ... Lb. 2 	 ... ... ... 	
Leave of Absence.—Leave of absence has been granted to the following officials of the Sudan Government and Army Officers : El Kaimakam Morant Bey, senior inspector, Kor-1
El Kaimakam Viscount W. H. Frankfort de Montmorency, Sudan Government, has resigned his commission in the Egyptian Army.
Another Bathing Fatality.—An Armenian tailor of the name of Sarkis, 35 years of age, was drowned whilst bathing in the sea near the fort Kaid Bey. His body has not yet been recovered.
Suez Canal.—10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 14th inst., 5 of which were British, 3 German, 1 Dutch, 1 French. The day’s receipts were frs. 296,350.28, making the total from the 1st inst frs. 3,997,052 18.
Coal Imports.—From the 1st January to the 14th September 710,731 tons of coal were imported into Egypt. Wales sent 382,998, Newcastle 161,433, Scotland 92,415, Yorkshire 45,736 and other places 26,149 tons. During the same period of 1904,715,501 tons were received.
dofan province, until November 25 ; El Bim-bashi Birley, Artillery, until November 26 ; El Bimbashi Hon. N. P. Macnaughten, junior inspector Suakin province, until December 1 ; El Bimbashi Spencer, assistant director of Surveys, until October 26. Extension of leave has been granted to El Kaimakam Carter Bey, officer commanding the 9th Sudanese, until November 22 ; El Bimbashi Airey, inspector, Bahr el Ghazal province, until October 22 ; El Bimbashi Elderton, deputy assistant financial secretary, Sudan Government, until October 25.

For the Calabrian Sufferers. — It is tonight that the special benefit performance will be given at the Alhambra Theatre by the Della Guardia Dramatic Company for the relief of the thousands of victims of the terrible earthquake which has devastated a great part of Calabria. We are glad to be able to announce that Alexandrians have responded well to the appeal for their support which has been made by the Press of this city, and that the "house” promises to be crowded in every part Yesterday afternoon a very large number of people went to Mex to assist at the "grand festival” which the management held for the same purpose, and the programme was a great success and warmly applauded throughout. A vocal concert in which some excellent singing was heard, was succeeded by the second part of the Italian drama XXIX Luglio, and this was followed by the Spanish zarzuela La Gran Via, but want of space prevents us referring to any of these in detaiL On Friday Cairo will congregate at the Esbekieh Theatre to witness the performance of Chemineau by the Gardet troupe, which is proving such a great attraction to Cairo theatre-goers, and the proceeds of this performance will also be devoted to the relief fund. The prices which have been fixed for the entertainment are as follows first boxes P.T. 120, second boxes P.T. 70 ; orchestra stalls P.T. 20 ; pit P.T. 15 ; gallery P.T. 5. As we have announced previously the comedy Came le Foglie will be staged at the Alhambra Theatre, Alexandria, this evening, and will be followed by the farce Meglio soli che male accompagnati.
Mr. Beresford Versehoyle is leaving Marseilles on the 22nd instant by the Bibby liner Yorksline.
The following are among the latest arrivals at the Windsor Hotel, Alexandria : Dr. Granville, Mr. and Mrs. Hague, Mr. and Mrs. Log, Dr. Morrogb, Mr. Britain, Mr. Maule, Mr. Osborne Sheppard, Mr. and Mrs. Econo-mou, Mr. Lebton, Mr. Mansfield, Mr. Goani-cles. Mr. Rifay, Mr. Belbary, Mr. H. Page, Mr. J. Page, Mr. Heyman, Mr. and Mrs. Holzer, Mr. Balesian, Mr. W. Lane, Mr. Hanauer, Lt. S. Grill, Mr. Wilson, Mr. Camming, Mr. Spathis, Mr. and Miss Levy, Mr. Morice, Mr. Porthos, Mr. Rossi, Mr. Nahas, Miss Selman. Dr. and Mme Betar, Mr. Nagal, Mr. Betesch, Mr. Joky, Bid Bey, M. Levasly, Mr Ernest de Gare, Mr. Moporgo, Dr. Goldslioh, Mr. Lonridl, Mr. Hugo Glowig, Mr. Galeel, Mr. Agiman, Mr. Aboucassem, Mr. Shopper, Mr. and Mrs, Stephens, two children.
18

0

4

40

24

4

7 2

8 2 4 2

115
A. C. C. bowling.

Mr. H. B. Carver .

Mr. P. P. Graves Mr. P. Byrne Mr. R. B. McLean
0. M. R. W.

10.	1. 34. 9.

11.	2. 83. 4. 8. 3. 29. 2. 6. 8. 17. 1.
A. C. C.

Mr. P. P- Graves, b. Sides	 0

„	T. H. Marsden. o. Murphy b, Moore	5

„	J. C. Maclaren, b. Sides		 21

„	C. D. Stacey, run out 	 69

„	H. B. Carver, b. Morrison	...*	...	50

„ K. Macaulay, b. Morrison 	 1

„ R. Carver, not ont	 8

„ K. Birley A

„ S. J. Dawson J

b. 10. L b. 3	 13

Total for 6 wickets	 167
Royal Berkshire Regiment Bowling.

0. M. R. W.
PASSENGER LIST.
DEPARTURES.
Pte. Sides Capt. Moore Pte. Crutch Mr. J. A. Robertson Loe. Corp. New Loe. Corp. Morrison
11. 3. 60. 2. 10. 1. 35. 1. 4. I. 14. — 3. — 12. — 2. — 15. — 1. 3.	9.	2.
Le paquebot Niger des Messageries Mariti-mes parti le 15 septembre poor Marseille,avait a bord :

MM. l’Abbe Potard,seize pelerine pelerinage Potard, Millar, dix-sept pklerins pdlerinage Potard, R. P. Xavier Witner. Mme Maurioe, Ph. J. Philippon, Mme 8. et D. B. Dickson, Birch, Perdigaohi, R. P. Chorro, S. Joannidks. Mile Carver,M. et Mme Crawley et bdbd, Mme Nine de Pervenohe et 47 passagers de 3e et 4e classes.

Lepsqnebot Imperatrix, du Lloyd Autii* chien parti samedi pour Trieste avait k bord:

MM. Ting. Liespeker, Dr Pertusi, Macaulay et filles, F. Kesel, Mile Avierino, M. de Avie-rino, M. Millington, H. Ramann, F. Sofio, A. Ruskovioh, ObermTller, Jager, Kirohmayer, Heinr Rudolf, Ph. Pfeiffer, A. V. Miran, A. Jom, De Martino, Dr R. Bergd et 24 passagers de 3me classe.
Fire in the Labban Quarter.—A slight outbreak of fire occurred in the Labban quarter yesterday in the house of an Italian named Espiro. Fortunately but little damage was done and the fire was quickly extinguished, but Espiro received severe burns, which necessitated his removal to hospital, and much of the furniture was burned. Inquiry proves the fire to have caused by lighted cigarette ends which were left lying on the floor.
BECK & CO’S PILSENER BEER

Obtainable fraas •vmry Raapaatahla Firm la Oaxsa, Auumu k m 8imx. GJforwto egfh

». J. riKUHVT,	h W5AU0- Sob Agent,

One,	iblwMfaUa, Awww*
LA LIQUIDATION DAIRA
A. S. C.

SEPTEMBER SKYE MEETING.

The following are the entries for the September S. M : —

H. H. Prinoe Omar Tonssoun’s Hadban and Shnei'oan Hussein Bey Sionfi’s Abou Nadara II., Mr. A. J. Suraook’s Ilaros, Mr. E. Karam’s B-iyard and Sbsibonb, Mr. H. Ekisler’s Temsah, H. E. Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Soheittan and Kbafif, H. K Moharrem-Pasha Chehin’s Cnpid and Derwish, Mr. N. Simond’s Derry Boy, Soleh Bey Yaghen’s Ibrahimieb, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs 8olferino, Sudan, and Fedhan, Isbaok Bey Hussein’s Nesaim.

Maiden Horse Raoe.—Mr. A. J. Snrsook’s Nigri, H B. Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Snheil, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs El Derwish and Orion.

Maiden Galloway Raoe.—Mr. A. J. Burdock's Roy-Blas, Mr. E. Karam’s Bayard, Mr. H Bkisler’s Bahr Nil, H. K Khalil Pasha Kh&yat’a Monrghan, H. R Moharrea Pasba Chehin’s Derwish and Cnpid, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs Aziz and Fedhan, Ishak BsyHussein’s Kismit

September Plato-Mr. H.	IWh.

H B Khalil Pasha Kbayat’s Saleik, Saleh Bey Ysghen’s Bulkeley, Ibrahim Bey Cherifand Blie Bey Sorsook’s Mikado, Ibrahim Bey Cherifs Sudan, Ishak Bey Hussein’s Neesim.

Autumn Stakes.—Mr. A. J. Miohaelides’ Jupiter, H. K Khalil Pasha Khayat’s Fil de Per and Korosko, H. R Moharrem Pasha Chehin’s Minand and Massond, (late An Revoir) Ibrahim Bey Cherifs Qeaette end Zen* Ii« I*h*ok BeyHoneh’i Bated,
WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant.

Takl. .'Hot. Lunoh.on. * Dlnn.r. 8«rr«. on th. TamM*

ORCHESTRA PLAY 6 TO 11.30 P.M

nuHffft	■*** ******
LE PROCES DES PRINCES
Comme suite aParticle paru dans lea oolon| nea de notre journal le 28 aofit dernier, sons mettons sons les yeux de nos lectears la oopie textuelle de l’assignation signifies par LL. AA. lea Princes et Prinoesses fils et filles de feu A. Ismail Pacha, Khedive d’Egypts, kl’oooa-sion de la revendication du prix des hints ven-dus par la Daira Sanieh Cy. Ltd: —

A la requkte de LL. AA les Prinoesses Dje* naniar et Toheem Afet Hanem, veuves de S.A Ismail Pacha, Khedive d'Egypte et de Id. A A les Prinoes Hussein Pacha Kamel, Ifcmhim Pacha He) mi, oelni-oi tant en son nom personnel qn’en sa quality de ourateur de son frkre interdit Mahmoud Pacha Hamdi, et Pouad Paoha Ahmed, les dits quatre requdrants fils de feu S.A. Ismail Paoha, tous propridtaires Ottomans demeurant an Cairo, et agissant en lent qnalitd d’hdritiere de feu S.A. Ismail Paoha, Khddive d’Egypte, aveo dleotion de domicile aux fins des prdsentes en l'dtude de Me Emile Manosardi, avooat an Cairo.

Je soussignd... hnissier prka le Tribunal Mixte da Cairo ai signifid et ddolard:

1° A la Daira Sanieh Company Limited.

2° A la Daira Sanieh de S. A le Khddive d’Egypte.

8° A 8. E. Mazlonm Paoha pris en sa qnalitd de Ministre des Finanoes da Gonvaro* meat Egyptian.

4° An Crddit Fonder Egyptian.

Qae mes reqadrants o nsidkrant qne tout le surplus da prix de vente des biens administrds par la Daira Sanieh de 8. A le Khddive, aprks le rembonreement de la dette Gdndrale de 1* Daira Sanieh et aprks rembonreement de toutes sommes pouvant dtre dues an Gouver-nement Egyptian, et aprks ddfeloation de toutes sommes pouvant revenir k la Daira Sanieh Company Limited par suite d’engagements pris k son profit en vne de la liquidation des biens Daira, et enfin >prhs remboune-ment de tons frais de tonte nature inhdrentsk la gestion des dits biens par la Daira Sanieh de S.A. le Khddive, leur appartient exolusive-ment et en tonte propridtd.

Qne partant et en tant quo de besoin fit eutendent revendiquer, oomme en effet par le prdaent aote ils revendiqoeat la propridtd ah* solue et exclusive de toutes sommes pouvant rdsnlter de la liquidation de la Daira Sanieh de S.A. le Khddive k la suite dee vantes dee biens de la dite Daira et aprks rkglemant de tout le passif de la dite liquidation dans lee oonditions oi-dessns indiqudes.

En oonsdquenoe je huissier sns-dit et sons-lignd agissant tonjoors k la mdme requdte qne dessas ai fait ddfense expreese et formelle:

1°A la Daira Sanieh Company Limited d’avoir k verser soit k la Daira de 8A. le Khddive, soit au Gonvernement Egyptian tonte somme dont elle pourrait raster d dbi trice apr&s rembonreement de toutes les sommes lui re* Tenant:

3° A la Daira Sanieh de 8. A le Khddive d’avoir k verser an Gonvernement Egyptian toutes sommes dont elle serait encore ddten-trioe aprks rembonrsement de la dette gdndrale de la Daira et aprks rembonreement des sommes pouvant ktre dikes pour frais, avanees on impdts arridrds, an Gonvernement Egyptian et aprks acquirement de tons les engagements par elle pris ainsi qo’il a did expliqud oi-demus.

Et de m6me suite et k rndme requdteje hnissier sasdit et Boussignd, ai donnd assignation aux signifies pins hant ddnommds'et qualifies d’avoir k oomparaltre devant le Tribunal Civil. Mixte da Cairo k Taudienoe de lnodi trente Ootobre 1905 k neuf heores da matin au lieu ordinaire de ses sdanoes au Palais de Justice en oette villa, pour lkdtent

Attendu qu’il ressort d’uue manikre dvi-dente et incontestable das Conclusions du rep-port de la Commission Snpdrienre d’enqukte institnde par dd.re* de S.A. le Khddive Ismail Paoha en dated'* 27 janvier 1878, oonoloricma aoceptdes par S.A. Ismail Paoha et qui formant partant la loi des parties, qua oe qua la dite Commission aentendu demandor k S.A Ismail Paoha et ce qne ce dernier a aooeptd de fair®, o’eet d’affeoter tons les biens aujoord’hui administrds par la Daira Sanieh k la liquidation da ddfioit et de oonfier oette liquidation k nne administration spdoiale ayant lee ponvoire lee pins dtendus, y oompris la feoultd d’alidner oa d’bypothdqner.

Attendu qae la Commission de liquidation qui 681 venue substituer la Commission Supd-rieore d’enqadte par les dispositions inadrdes dans la loi de liquidation, n’a fait qua rdaliser et mettre k dxdoution l’aooord intervena en 1878 entre S.A. Ismsfl Paoha et la Commission Sapdrieore d’enqudte ; acoord que la Commission de liquidation a oonsiddrd oomme ddfiniti-roment acquis k l’Etat, mais acqael fl dtait impossible de donner dxdoution sous forme de oontrat, vu 1’absenoe de l’Bgypte de S. A Ismail Paoha; d’oh la ndoessitd de remplaoer oette exd-oution oontraotuelle par one disposition de loi.

Attendu qu’k l’oooafion de oette disposition

de loi la Commission de liquidation, qui d’aii* lean avait en le mandat de a'inspirer des conclusions de la Commission 8apdrieure d’en-qadte a tenu k bien dtablir dans aa sdanoe du 3 Jain 1880 qa’il n’y avait pas lieu de parier de oession oonsentie par 8. Ale Khddive Ismail, oar celui-oi s’dtait bornd k accepter les oonolu-sions du rapport de la Commission d’sDqudte oh il n’est pas question de oession proprement dite, mais implement de Taffsotatkm das do* maines de la Daira k la liquidation du ddfioit

Qu’ainsi dono la disposition da l'art 40 de la loi de liquidation, expliqudepar la djsoussion qui Pa prdoddde, ne saurait dtre intarprdtde dans le sens invoqud par le Gouverntment d’nnevdritable oonfitoation, mais nniquemant oomme nne mnotioo donnds k l’aooord da 1878 dans ana forma qui an randlt pomihfe IVtefe*: tioapar 1* substitution da l*Btet wKjyg mail netent Um Hriaadu