THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, THURSDAY SEPTEMBER 21, 1905.
SCANDINAVIAN CRISIS.
HOPES OF SETTLEMENT.
Karlstad, September 20.

The Swedo-Norwegian conference continues. While the main question, regarding the demolition CD the Norwegian fortresses and the eventual reference to arbitration of certain other questions, are virtually agreed upon, other knotty points are still unsettled, but it is believed that they will be adjusted satisfactorily. Meanwhile troops are kept in the neighbourhood of the frontiers. (Reuter)
FRANCE AND GERMANY.
HITCH IN NEGOTIATIONS.

Paris, September 20.

It is stated here that there is a hitch in the negotiations with regard to Morocco, due to the French anxiety for a precise definition of their special rights for policing the frontier. An authoritative Gorman statement declares that further serious difference is impossible.

(Reuter)
GERMAN SOCIALISTIC CONGRESS.
THE GOVERNMENT AND MOROCCO.

Jena, September 20.

The Socialistic Congress has refused to censure the attitude of the Government with regards to Parliament’s action concerning

Morocco.
GERMANY CONVOY CAPTURED.
SURPRISED BY HOTTENTOTS.

Cape Town, September 20.

The Hottentots have captured a German convoy near Kietmanshoep. The escort was surprised and practically annihilated. A thousand cattle, 122 waggons, some of which were laden with ammunition, and a number of rifles were captured.	(Reuter)
ITALY AND THE MULLAH.
RAIDS OF MIJERTAIN TRIBES.

Rome, September 20.

Advices from Somaliland state that the Mullah has complained to Italy of the raids of certain Mijertain tribes in the Italian sphere. The attempt of the Italian warships to arrange a settlement through the Sultan of the Mijer-
tains has failed.
(Reuter)
RUSSIAN FREEDOM.
EAST-ASIATIC SERVICE
RUSSIA’S NAVY.
LOCAL AND GENERAL.
The Plague.-Yesterday’s plague bulletin reporta one death in hospital at Alexandria.
Sale of Land.-We are informed that Dr. Varenhorst Pasha has sold a large site at Ramleh to the Egyptian Trust and Investment Company.
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Bonlac district of Cairo during to-morrow night and at dawn of the 23 rd inst will bo poisoned by the police.
Suez Canal.—10 vessels passed through the Canal on the 18th inst, 8 of which were British, 1 German, 1 French. The day’s receipts were frs. 328,966 16, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 5,055,79°.80.
The Railways Administration.—As a result of the public competitive examination held by the Railways Administration MM. Ugo Rossetto and Emile Arian have been appointed assistant engineers, the former at Embabeh and the latter at Alexandria.
San Stefano Casino.—Wo are asked to announce that those who reserve seats for dinner at the San Stefano Casino on Saturday will be admitted to the subscribers’ grand ball. Subscribers are asked to note that no invitations will be issued, but that their subscription tickets will gain admittance for them.
Sudan Government Transfers—El Bim-bashi A.A.C. Taylor, junior inspector of the Bahr el Ghazal province has been transferred to a similar post in the Berber province ; El Bimbashi H.W. Channer, 3rd Battalion transferred to the Sudan Government, has been appointed junior inspector of the Bahr el Ghazal province, has been retransferred to the Army ; Mr. W.E Drommond Hay, deputy-inspector in the Finance Department has been appointed junior inspector therein.
UKASE TO BE GRANTED.

London, September 20.

The “Times” learns from St. Petersburg that an ukase granting freedom of meeting, of Speech, and of the press, and the immunity from arbitrary arrest, will be promulgated as soon as the measures can be drafted. (Reuter)
RUSSIAN VOLUNTEER FLEET DELAYS.

Odessa, September 20.

The departure of the Volunteer steamers and others bound for Vladivostok has been deferred, pending the abrogation of Japan's right of capture.	(Reuter,
London, September 20. The “Daily News” states that a Russian Government agent in London is negotiating for the construction of the whole new navy in Great Britain.	(Reuter)
GREECE AND ROUMANIA.
Athens, September 20. The Hellenic Minister at Bucharest and the Roumanian Minister at Athens have gone on leave without being replaced.	(Havas)
M. WITTE VISITS M. LOUBET.
Ministry of Finance. - The following modifications, to date from the 1st October, will take place in the duties of the inspectors and sub inspectors consequent on the absence on leave of Mr. Etherington Smith and Burnett Stuart: —Inspector Haines will bo in charge of Menoufieh, Galioubieh and Dakahlieh provinces, inspector Mohamed Effendi Housny will be in charge of the Mudiriehs of Keneh, Guirgeh and Assouan and inspector Dallin will be in charge of the Gharbieh and Bahera provinces.
THE SUCRERIES.
FEATURES OF CONCORDAT.
NOTES FROM PORT SAID.
NIGHT NAVIGATION IN THE CANAL
LETTER TO THE EDITOR.

We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed

by our correspondents, but we wish

to all, to permit --- within certain necessary limits
A reprieve saves a prisoner from being hanged, it does not necessarily carry with it an order of his instant release from gaol. Such is the character of the concordat préventif ; it staves off a sudden and reverberating financial crash, but it may only delay a compulsory liquidation. In the case of the Sucreries, we hope for the sake of the country that the respite will enable the company to reorganise and recover, but while we recognise this pleasant possibility, we cannot shut our eyes to the fact that nothing in the decision of the, Cairo Mixed Court can be taken as a guarantee that the compulsory winding-up of the company will not eventually become necessary. Article 206 (new) of the Mixed Code gives the terms on which a person or corporation is allowed to enjoy the benefit of the concordat préventif. Its chief features are these. The appointment by the tribunal of one of its members, the “juge commissaire” who takes and goes through the debtor’s books and finds his exact financial situation, decides under what conditions if any, the debtor can continue to do business, calls a meeting of the creditors, reads them a report on the situation, on the question of the debtor’s good faith and his proposals.

Once the juge commissaire is appointed the debtor ceases payments by right.

The names of the administrators under the concordat suggested by Maitre Carton de Wiart have been formally accepted by the Court. M. Debourg, we understand, will sign for his colleagues, Sir Elwin Palmer and Harari Pasha, during their absence.

NEW HOTELS IN CAIRO.
Besides the National and the New Khedi-vial, the former in the Sharia Soliman Pasha, and the latter in the Sharia Bab-el-Hadid, both of which are announced to open on the 1st November, we learn that a well-known Swiss group are in treaty for the purchase of the Khedivah-Mother’s palace in the Kasr-el-Donbara quarter, for the propose of transforming it into a first-class hotel, whilst the representative of another syndicate just arrived in Cairo has been making enquiries for acquiring property in the Opera Square, also with the intention of erecting a large up-to-date hotel with a splendid arcade of shops underneath. We shall publish fuller details of both projects as soon as the negotiations now in progress are completed.

A DRAMA OF THE DESERT.
For the Calabrian Sufferers.—We would once more appeal to our Alexandria readers to support a benefit performance for the relief of the victims of the Calabrian earthquake. To-morrow night the Società Filodrammatica la Margherita will hold a ''soirée de gala” at the Eden Theatre for the benefit of the sufferers, and have arranged a programme which cannot fail to please any audience. This society Will present the Italian comedy Infidele, which will be followed by the farce II Cuoco ed il Segretario, and the Armenian band will play selections during the intervals.
Société Réunion des Familles —A grand fête will be given by the Société Réunion des Families at the Mex Casino on Saturday, commencing at 9.30 p.m. The programme will include a ball, and a vocal and instrumental concert in which Mlles. G. Capozzi and M. Tortella, and MM. G. Sacco, J. Andresti, andE. Chaloub will take part. The Armenian band will provide the music for the dances, of which no fewer than twenty-one appear on the programme, including polkas, waltzes, lancers, barn-door dance, pas des patineurs, a moulinet du pas de quatre, a galop, and the inevitable cake-walk. At 1 a.m. there will be a grand quadrille, as an adieu to the Mex season, and at 2 a.m. a lottery for thirty prizes will be drawn. The casino will be brilliantly illuminated à la Vénitienne, and there will also be a firework display. The entertainment will be under the patronage of Baron E. Acton, consul-general for Italy, and the proceeds of the lottery will be given to the relief fund for the victims of the Calabrian earthquake, two circumstances which cannot fail to attract large crowds.
Paris, September 20.

M. Witte has gone to Valencia to visit M. Loubet.	(Havas)
DEATH OF DR. BARNARDO.
London, September 20. The philanthropist Dr. T. T. Banardo has died.	(Reuter)
We have pleasure in calling the attention of our readers to the splendid preparation of Messrs. Allen & Hanburys, Ltd., the celebrat-ed London chemists, which is being offered for sale under the title of "Allenburys’ Diet.” It would seem to be specially suitable for our climate, where the best of milk is not always obtainable. We are informed that Messrs. Allenburys’ Diet is a complete food in itself for invalids, convalescents, and the aged. It is very palatable, easily prepared, and when. taken before bed-time will be found to induce sleep. Allenburys’ Diet can be carried to advantage by tourists travelling at home or abroad. It is made in a minute, and is very easy of assimilation. [Advt.]

We beg to call our readers’ attention to “Tozer’s Handbook of Foreign Consular and Customs Regulations,” (Wm. Agnew, 24 Mark Line, E.C. 1s/- net). Merchants and Shippers will find this a very useful addition to their reference library. It contains all the Consular and Customs regulations for various ports throughout the world. [Advt.]
WINDSOR HOTEL Restaurant

Tabla ë’Hata Lu nolisons A, Dlnnara Sarvatf aa tha Tarea##.

ORCHESTRA PLATS 8 TO 11.80 P M mpqroi »«a Mfpyiw
(From our Correspondent.)

Port Said, Tuesday.

Night navigation is now permitted, subject to certain conditions as to the beams of vessels and their power, though it is at their captain’s own risk. The Bibby line Lancashire was, I believe, the first ship to avail herself of the permission, and she arrived here safely late on Monday night.

Great interest is felt here in the coming of the members of the commission, some are to arrive to-morrow, but they will await the arrival of the “Chef du Transit” who comes on the M.M.Salazie. Rumours and wild stories are rife in the town regarding the various, proposals that have been made about the unfortunate Chatham, but I think I can safely say, that nothing is as yet decided nor will anything be until the gentlemen, whose arrival is so anxiously looked for, have carefully gone into the matter themselves.
NAVAL NOTES.

H.M.S. Sirius, the second-class cruiser which is expected at Suez to-morrow, is to transit the Canal at once, provided she does not receive orders there to undertake the investigation and punishment of the offenders in the recent Red Sea piracies. It is currently reported here that her captain is to return south and go into this matter at once.

The Sirius is a vessel of 3,600 tons displacement, having a speed of 19.75 knots and is armed with eight heavy guns.

The Terrible, Powerful and Renown are expected here in a short time, but doubt is expressed as to their ability to pass the Chatham, they all being of immense proportions.

ARRIVAL OF EXPLOSIVE EXPERTS.

Wednesday.

Messrs. Harris, Thomson and Cunningham experts of Nobell’s factory, together with M. Coullant and the various chiefs of the Suez Canal Company, arrived by the Brindisi mail this morning, and proceeded to the wreck of the Chatham, where lengthy deliberations were held, the results of which are unknown.

NOTABLE PASSENGER8,

The S.S. Tebe which arrived here yesterday morning had on board Marquis de Sangui-lians, Prof. Bosco, Conte Deciani, and various other members of a colonial Congress which proceeds to Asmara, close to Masawa. They dined with Conte Mancinelli Scotti at the Eastern Exchange, and proceeded through the Canal in the afternoon.

GALA PERFORMANCE AT ELDORADO.

In connection with the recent subscriptions which have been raised in aid of the sufferers from the Calabrian earthquakes, a gala perfor mance has been arranged for to night at the. Eldorado Theatre. Various members of the Consular staff here have formed themselves into a committee. The whole of the audi-torum of the theatre has been taken up and many subscriptions have been collected, among which the Comité de Bienfaisance has subscribed frs. 150.
In our issue of the 13st instant we mentioned that advice bad been received from Assiout by the Ministry of the Interior that two camel-men, accompanied by a policeman, who had left there the previous week, having in their charge some money for the pay of the police at the Oasis, bad been murdered, and that the policeman who returned to Assiout with the news was wounded in the bead. As the money was found intact it was at once seen that the motive for the crime could not have been robbery. An enquiry was at once instituted by the local Parquet and the mamour of the district, while a force of police was sent in search of the murderers who, the wounded policeman averred, were brigands. As no tracks could be found near the spot where the murders had been committed suspicion was aroused,and the policeman was suspected of having been guilty of the deed himself. It now appears that the latter was accompanied by his wife, and three traders also went with the caravan.

From the evidence of the latter it now transpires that it was the policeman himself who shot the camelman, (not two as originally reported), in consequence of having discovered an intrigue between him and the woman. On hearing the report of a gun one of the traders rushed out of his tent to discover the cause, and was himself also shot dead. The medical man who examined the wounded policeman was of opinion that the wounds he bore in the head were self inflicted, and such turns out to be the case. This man, who is now in hospital, has been placed under arrest, and will be tried for the murders as soon as he is sufficiently recovered.
ITALIAN NATIONAL FETE.
The fete in honor of the unification of Italy which was held last night at the Alhambra Theatre was a great success. Baron Acton and most of the principal members of the Italian Colony were present, and the audience was most patriotic. After the opening of the fete with the National hymn, which was loudly applauded, an eloquent speech by Mr. Zucchi arroused the enthusiasm of all present The  pupils of the Conservatoire then gave a pretty rendering of an air by M. Colella, and then came the delightful comedy Nessuno va al campo and other historical pieces and recitations. The fireworks and, illuminations were capital, the charity bazaar and its lottery for the victims of the Calabrian Earthquake a great financial success, and the Khedive’s military hand with that of the Greeek Phil harmonic Society as well as the orchestra ably directed by Professor Gianni Galetti, were greatly appreciated. A vocal and instrumental concert with selections from La Poupee, Mascotte, Tosca, etc., and the performances of a conjuror-illusionist, finished the evening very pleasantly.
A PETITION.

An energetic young official, while on inspection in the Delta recently, received the following pathetic appeal:—

Sir,—I have the honour to inform you that as I am a poor, have a large family, working alone without any help, I ask you kindly to forgive me and send a permission to the Police Office by which it forgives me also, I sent this hoping that your honesty and pardon are well known over the globes and at last I call out “God save our Inspector.”

I am your obedient servant,

M.A.E A BUTCHER.

CORPORATION OP WESTERN EGYPT LTD.

Mr. H. J. L. Beadnell, F. G. S., F. R. G. S., Manager in the Oases and Geological Expert, is now en route to Egypt to take up his appointment.

NILE VALLEY.

The “Financier” announces on September 13 that the manager cables corrected returns from the battery for August;—Total amount crushed-, 405 tons, yielding 865 oz of gold. Have struck rich ore 200 ft level north ; extent at present unknown.—Office note. :—A cable has been sent to the manager requesting full information as to the rich chute mentioned in the above cable.
STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
The Moss liner Menes sailed from Malta yesterday afternoon and is due here on Saturday afternoon, with passengers, mails, and general cargo.

The Khedivial mail steamship Assouan will leave Alexandria at 4 p m. on Sunday and Port Said at 4 p.m, on Monday for Beyrouth, Tripoli, Mersina, Alexandretta, Larnacs, Limassol, Caiffa and Jaffa.

The M.M. Niger which left Alexandria on the 15th inst. arrived at Marseilles yesterday morning.
SUDAN GOLDFIELD, LIMITED.

Application has been made to the Committee of the London Stock Exchange to appoint a special settling day in Sudan Goldfield, limited—125,000 Vendors’ Shares of ₤1 each fully paid, Nos. 1 to 146,000.
EGYPTIAN SHARE MARKET.
EGYPTIAN SILVER CURRENCY,
To THE Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.

Sir,—With reference, to your article of the 21st ult., your leader writer appears to have so misunderstood some of the suggestions made by Mr. Roussin as to the rules to be followed in calculating the tature currency needs of Egypt, that I should like to be allowed to criticise the critique.

The regulation of a token currency is a. comparatively simple matter, and does not give rise to the divergent theories that exist, for instance,  in the case of paper currency. This is because a token currency regulates itself, the rôle of the Government being confined in ordinary circumstances to the replenishment of its stock when it is getting low, as is done, for instance, in England.

Something more than this is necessary in Egypt, because if the government waited till its holding began to get low, the new supplies could not be minted in time to meet the the demand. This makes itself felt at one season of the year only, i.e. during the cotton season in October, and November, while the silver takes three months to arrive from date of order. The instructions, to the Mint must therefore be given not later than July, supposing that it is necessary to make fresh provision.

In July and August the Government hold ing reaches its maximum (i e. the. circulation reaches its minimum) so instead of ordering new supplies, when stock is running, low, the somewhat paradoxical rule of ordering that just at the moment when there is most in band has to be adopted.

The data available for determining the amount to be ordered are as follows :

1.	The demand for extra coin for the cotton crop includes and greatly exceeds the amount required to inorease the permanent circulation. The public takes what it wants for the cotton crop, retains what it necessary for increase in circulation owing to growth of population, etc., and returns the rest, when the marketing of the crop is practically over, into the hands of the Government. Thus last winter the public took out LE 360.000 in silver, of which the Government received book L.E. 200.000 daring the spring and summer of this year, the balance of LE 160.000 being retained as the permanent addition to the circulation. Hence it is obvious that there is not the slightest necessity to consider any of the points detailed by your leader-writer. The Government by providing for the cotton crop and for that alone, provides ipso facto much more than enough for all other contingencies.

2.	The figures for past seasons show that the demand for the crop varies roughly according to its price, its quantity and the rapid-ity with which it is brought to market, But at the time it is necessary to order coin, none of, these factors can be foretold with any pretention to accuracy, and “keeping in touch with banks and markets” is of very little help. Therefore the only safe course is to presuppose a crop of maximum quantity at a very high price, and provide for that always.
3. To do this it becomes imperative to fix the minimum, corresponding with the above-mentioned contingency, below which the Government reserve at the opening of the cotton season most not be allowed to descend. The experience of past years shows that even in season of record crop and prices, the expansion. in the winter circulation has never-reached £400,000. That amount has there fore been chosen as the irreducible minimum the Government must have in band. This rule is not a fixed one, since it does not prevent the Government from providing any amount over the minimum which it may deem advisable.

Had this policy been initiated earlier, there would have been no impediment to the automatic self regulation of the currency, and no scarcity would have occured.—I am, Sir, etc.	Fiscal.

London, September 12.
PERSONAL AND SOCIAL
Sir William Willcocks, returns to Cairo with Lady Willcocks at the end of this month.
El Miralai G. Harvey Pasha, Ministry of the Interior, has been granted leave of absence until November 11.
Khalil Pasha Hamada left for Cairo yesterday afternoon.
M. Hann von Hanneheim, Austro-Hungarian Consul at Cairo, has returned and resumed

his functions.
Mr. Borton, assistant postmaster general, has left for a tour of inspection in Middle Egypt.
The condition of the Duke d’Andria who broke his leg on the S.S. Tebe when about to go on shore, is satisfactory.
Among the latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel, Port Said, we notice:-Brigadier General S. M. Bullock, Captain and Mrs. Moore, Mr. R. A. Coloni, Mr. O. Bentley, Mr.
(From our Financial CORRESPONDENT.

London. September 15th

During the latter part of the week the Stock

Exchange  has been occupied with the fort-

nightly settlement, which has been an unusually heavy one, owing to the large increase in business which is now taking, place. The

directors of the Bank of England decided on

Thursday last to make no change in the Bank rate. 

Pending their decision, prices were heavy,

 but as soon as it was known that they had made no alteration, buoyancy all round was the order of the day. The Bank returns show that notwithstanding the large withdrawals of gold, the reserve had only fallen ₤189,000 owing to the reflux of coin and notes from circulation here; and this now stands at. £24,506,000. There is still a feeing that the demand for gold for Egypt and South America must increase, and consequently it is thought probable that a higher rate will prevail in the autumn ; even a 4% rate should not be detrimental, as the signs of improvement in trade throughout the country are becoming more evident every day. Consols, which were as low as 895/8 rose to 8913/16 , and close to day at the latter price. In the foreign market, Japanese bonds were firmer on a good demand, the First Four-and-a-half percent rising 1/4 to 947/8  and the Second 1/8 to 33/4 premium. They leave off at 943/4 and 33/4 premium respectively 

Russians remain unchanged, with the exception of a nominal rise of 11/3  in the Fives,

Home Rails show little change on since last week, with the exception that Southern stocks have advanced slightly. The American market has been active with a reaction in prices which is considered only 

natural after the recent advances. Reports from the United States are most optimistic both as regards the condition of the crops and the trade outlook. Consequently higher prices are looked for all round during the winter months.

In the Egyptian section there has been some good buying of the shares of the Anglo-Egyptian Bank. The company, it is stated, has had an exceedingly profitable year, National  Banks are firm at 273/4  and Agricultural Banks maintain their prices at 14 5/8. A new franco-Egyptian Bank has been formed under English law, with a capital of £500,000 in £5 shares. The whole this amount has been placed and the £5 are now quoted on the Paris Bourse at 61/4. This bank is con-nected with the Credit Mobilier in Paris and the Credito Mobiliare in Italy. which was current in the early park of the week that Sir Ernest Cassel, was interested in the promotion with the idea of assisting the reconstruction of the Societe des Sucreries et Raffinerie d’Egypte is quite incorrect.

Now that most of the parties interested in the above concern are in Cairo you will proba-bly be obtaining earlier information as to the course of events in connection with the ********** of this company ; the understanding here, however, is that it will be granted the benefit of the concordat preventif. The shares of the Daira Sugar Company are quoted today at 43/4.

In the mining section the continued interest in Rhodesian shares has had a good effect on the market generally, and if this continues we shall see higher prices in almost all sections Nile Valle, to which we called attention when they stood, at 15/— have been as high 13/8 with good-buying, due to a belief in the satisfactory settlement of the Robinson interest and also to the report from the manager that a good crushing of 405 tons yielded 365 ounces of gold. The Egyptian Mines Exploration group are firm as the result of the development in the Semna mine of the Fatira Company particulars

of which appear elsewhere.
SPORT AND PLAY

KHEDIVIAL YACHT CLUB.



REGATTA.

The following is the result of yesterday's

Class I.

Boat	Start Finish Sailed by

1	Sana Pareille 3.50.55 5.09.10 H. de Tachudi

2 Leman	3.40.28 5.1 1.45 C. Redocanachi

3	Tier-el-Mina 3.82.18	5.11.50 Capt Borg

Banshee	3.44.07	5.13.45 T. McClure

Celtic	3.38.20	5.16.02 Capt Evans

Coot	3.33.40	5.32.40 Sagh. Curwen

Class II.

1	Akraba	3.52.37	5 87.04 Sagh. Phillips

2	Masr	4 04.33	5.38.40 Mr. P. Ott

3	Calypso	4.07.18	5.89.17 O. Werner

Jessica	3.52.52	5.42.45 Grafton Bay

Cattelaya       3.51.20 gave up M.P. Hopkinson

SEPTEMBER SKYE MEETING.

The September Skye Meeting, the list of entries for which have already appeared in our columns, will be held on Saturday afternoon.

ESBEKIEH GARDENS

By kind permission of Lient Colonel 	R. C. C.

Cox commanding, and

the 2nd Royal Innis killing Fusiliers will perform

the following programme of music at the Esbekieh Gardens tomorrow, Tuesday evening commencing at 9 o'clock.

Overture - "Egmont" - Beethoven

Cornet Solo -"A Child's Song of Hope"-Myddleton Selection-"La Gioconda"--Ponchiello Walzer - "An'er Sohonen Blauen Donan" -Strauss

Musical Idyll—“The Smithy in the Wood"--Mikado Selection--"In Fille de madame Angri" - Lepoq

Merry Interlude--"Let's be Lively"--Myddleton

	Regimental March--Khedieval

		God Save the King
