THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, FRIDAY SEPTEMBER 22, 1905.
TURKISH OUTRAGE.
BOMBS IN BRITISH SUBJECT’S HOUSE,
WHO PUT THEM THERE?
Constantinople, September 21.

Acting on information given by the Arme nians, a porter of a British subject's house has been arrested here in connection with the bomb explosion on the 21st July. The house was searched and 5 empty bombs and 15 bottles of explosive liquid were discovered in a well.

(Reuter)
RUSSIA AND JAPAN.
ARMISTICE ON SEA.

Tokio, September 21.

Admirals Jessen and Shimamura concluded a naval armistice on the 18th instant. The narrowest portion of the Straits of Tartary will remain neutral. Admiral Shimamura granted a pass to a steamer with provisions for Kamchatka which will soon be icebound. (R.)
Vladivostock, September 21. The Russo-Japanese conference has settled the armistice on sea.	(Havas)
THE CAUCASUS REVOLT.
CONFERENCE OF OFFICIALS.

St. Petersburg, September 21.

A conference of high officials will meet here to concert radical measures for restoring order and security in the Caucasus.	(Reuter)
THUNDERSTORMS IN CALABRIA.
TEMPORARY SHELTERS DESTROYED.

Catanzaro, September 21.

Terrific thunderstorms and gales are augmenting the miseries of the earthquake sufferers, and levelling the tents and temporary shelters to the ground. Slight shocks of earthquake still continue.	(Reuter)
LOCAL AND GENERAL
The Plague—Yesterdays plague bulletin reports three recoveries at Alexandria. No fresh cases have been notified.
Fair Suppressed —We are informed that the Government has decided not to authorise the holding of the El Badoni fair at Tantah this year.
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Shoubra district of Cairo during tomorrow night and at dawn of the 24th instant will be poisoned by the police.
Suez Canal—8 vessels passed through the Canal on the 19th inst. of which 3 were British, 1 Dutch, 1 Italian, 1 Danish, 2 Austrian. The day’s receipts were frs. 298,851.78 making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 5,284,651.58.
Cairo Improvements — The Ministry of Public Works has decided that the part of the Bonlac canal which has been filled up, from the Ismailieh Canal to the Shoubra bridge, is to be converted into a street sixteen metres in breadth.
The Eden Theatre.— We are asked to remind our readers that the Società Filo-drammatic la Margherita will hold a “soirée de gala” at the Eden Theatre this evening for the benefit of the victims of the Calabrian earthquake.
A Gun Accident.—A Greek groom, Nicola Petros by name, was shot in the head yester-day whilst carelessly handling a charged gun belonging to a gaffir. The injured man was removed to hospital and it is hoped that the shot will not prove fatal.
AMERICAN INSURANCE COMPANIES.
ASTONISHING IRREGULARITIES DISCLOSED.

New York, September 21.

The official investigation which is proceeding here, into the affairs of the leading American Insurance Companies has disclosed astonishing irregularities of large loan transactions which were not recorded in the proper books and heavy advances of funds to parties and persons for political purposes.	(Reuter)
THE KARLSTAD CONFERENCE.
Stockholm, September 21. The Swedish and Norwegian Parliaments will meet on the tenth of October to discuss the result of the Karlstad conference. (Reuter)
CROWD STORMS RIGA PRISONS.
Riga, September 21.

The crowd stormed the prisons and killed or wounded five guards. They liberated two important political criminals.	(Reuter)
GERMAN SOCIALISTIC CONGRESS.
Jena, September 21.

The socialistic congress has voted the celebration of the first of May.	(Havas)
CHOLERA AT LODZ.
Lodz, September 21.

Three deaths from Asiatic cholera are notified here.	(Havas)
THE SIRDAR’S RETURN.
London, September 21. Sir Reginald Wingate has left for Khartoum (Reuters)
DEATH OF COLONEL RHODES.
Helouan.—The Ministry of the Interior has decided that in future all the localities situated between Helouan and Old Cairo shall form part of the Helouan district. From the 1st January, the town, together with the localities in question, will be placed under the Cairo gouvernorat, and a now police post will be established at Tourah.
Immigration to the Sudan.—A Cairo contemporary states that seventy five Sudanese living at Assouan have begged the Government to repatriate them. Owing to their poverty, it has been decided to send them up country at the Government expense and give them lands in the White Nile district, south of Khartoum.
Winch Accidents.— A native porter, called Hanna Gairgis, was struck by a winch whilst discharging cargo from the hold of a Prince line steamer in dock. The man’s hands were injured and it will be some time before he is able to resume work. Unfortunately another winch accident on a different boat of the same line, which happened to a porter called Neguib Ammar, ended fatally, the man being struck on the head.
The Ghezireh Charity Sale. — The Committee who are organising the charity sale and fete champêtre, which is to be held at the Theatre des Ambassadeurs in Cairo in aid of the victims of the Calabrian earthquake, desire us to mention that amongst the entertainments to be provided is a lottery, the prizes for which will be objects of art generously offered by several of the leading establishments of the metropolis. The band of the Rifle Brigade and-that of the Egyptian Cavalry will perform in the grounds of the theatre during the afternoon.
OBITUARY.
London, September 21 Colonel Frank Rhodes has died of black water fever at Cape Town.	(Reuter)

Colonel Francis William Rhodes, C.B., was born on April 5, 1851, and was the son of the late Rev. F. W. Rhodes and brother of the late Cecil Rhodes. He was educated at Eton and joined the 1st Dragoons, and was also managing director of the African trans-continental telegraph company. He served both in the Sudan and in South Africa during the Boer war, when he was mentioned in the despatches. He was military secretary to the Governor of Bombay, and later Governor of Mashonaland and Matabeleland. He retired from active service in 1908,
COLONEL TULLY, V.D.

The death took place at Croydon, on Septem ber 14, of Colonel Thomas Tolly, V.D., com-mandant of the 4th V.B. East Surrey Regiment. His first connexion with the Volunteers dates from 1861, when he joined the 4th City of London, Foresters, Rifles, with whom he was on duty when the Queen, then Princess Alexandra, arrived in London. After service with the London Irish Rifles and the Tower Hamlets Rifle Brigade, he took command of the 4th East Surrey Regiment in 1899. He acted as the honorary secretary of what was known in 1883 as the Grand Military Tournament at Islington, in connexion with which he worked in active co-operation with Lord Methuen; and he was afterwards appointed the permanent secretary of the Royal Military Tournament, holding the office until 1895, when presentations from Army officers were made to him and his wife in recognition of his work. Colonel Tally was one of the organisers of the English women’s Jubilee offering to Queen Victoria in 1887; and in recognition of his work in this connexion he received from her Majesty the silver commemoration medal and a signed photograph, together with a letter of thanks. Colonel Tally also acted as secretary to the Egyptian war fund, and was for some time secretary of the Home District Tactical and War Game Society. Only on the previous  Tuesday evening it was announced that the King bad conferred the Victorian Order upon him.
A NEW COMPANY.
LAND ALLOTMENT.
Our Cairo correspondent informs us that a new company, which will be known as the Anglo-Egyptian Land Allotment Company, has been formed and will issue its prospectus in the latter half of October. The capital of the new company will amount to L.E. 500,000 in L.E. 4 shares, and its operations will, we understand, be confined to the purchase of land which it will sell in allotments of all sizes to the peasantry ; and to the lease of lands which it will sub-let after improvements, to individuals who are not in a position to buy, but can afford to pay a moderate rent. The company will be purely an Egyptian concern, its head-quarters will be in Cairo, though we hear that a locality has not yet been selected. This, however, is of small importance to the public compared with the constitution of the board of directors.

This body consists of three British and five Native members. Sir William Willcocks will be chairman of the new company, its manager will be Captain Westrop of the Daira Sanieh, while the third British member of the board holds an important post in one of the Egyptian banks, whose name will be published on receipt of the authority of the bank directors.

The native members of the board are Hassan Pasha Asem, late grand master of ceremonies to H.H. the Khedive, Hassan Pasha Abd el Razzak, a notable of Minieh and member of the Legislative Council, Mahmoud Bey Abd el Gaffar, also a member of the Legislative Council and a notable of Menoufieh, Mahmoud Bey Rassim, ex-president of the Assiout Court of Appeal and member of the committee of Judi-cial Surveillance, and Mohamed Bey Metwalli, a notable of Gharbieh and a well-known land expert

The promoters of the company are Messrs. Yussef Bey Sadik and Co. Yussef Bey Sadlik has lately visited London and Paris on behalf of the now company, which will, we understand, be brought out through the Anglo-Egyptian Bank, Ltd. Maitre Carton de Wiart will be the legal adviser of the company, the formation of which has greatly interested financial circles both in Cairo and Alexandria. The subscription will probably open shortly before the end of next month.
THE SUCRERIES.
The experts appointed by the “juge com-missaire,” Mr. Somerville Tuck, to enquire into the actual condition of the Sucreries Company are M. Fonrneron Bey, engineering expert and engineer in chief to the Daira, Sanieh, Nonrrisson Bey, agricultural expert, and M.Sampaolo. whose knowledge of accounts and book-keeping is universally recognised in Egypt. The judge's choices seem to us to be admirable, and by the 4th October the experts he has appointed should be in a position to inform the meeting convoked on that day what the situation really is. Once more the shareholder must wait.
NEWSPAPER PROSECUTION.
The charge brought against Ahmed Fouad, editor of the “Sayeka” or the “Thunderer’’ by Sheik Ali Yusef, the well-known editor and proprietor of “El Moayad,” will come on for hearing before the tribunal of Saida Zenab on Monday next. The original charge, as mentioned in our issue of the 12th instant, was attempt at blackmailing, but the Procurer General, to whom the dossier of the case was submitted by the Parquet, decided that there was no evidence to support the graver charge before the Assize Court. The accused will now be tried for the minor one of libel.
THE LATE M. MABARDI.
The funeral of the late M. Aziz Georges Mabardi, the well-known partner in the firm of Steinmann, Mabardi & Co., of Alexandria, who died at Mammern, Switzerland, took place on Wednesday afternoon. The service was held at the Syrian Catholic Church in the Rue Debbane, to which the body had been removed on its arrival by the Florio-Rubattino mail boat, and was attended by a very large number of the many friends of the deceased. After the ceremony  the fanerai cortège proceeded along the Rue Cherif Pasha to the Syrian Catholic Cemetery, where the body was laid in its last resting place. Three carriages filled with most beautiful floral tributes formed part of the precession, and there were also many wreaths on the bier.
CONSULAR REPORTS ON EGYPT
SUEZ.
Mr. pro Consul Laferla reports that the trade of Suez for the year 1904 amounted to L.E. 1,486,420 showing an increase of L.E. 161,182 over the figures of the previous year. Of the imports, coal fell off, only 10,497 tons being landed against 55,644 tons in 1903 and we do not notice any reason given for this curious fall. The imports of tobacco, spices and live cattle and sheep showed an increase, 15,202 more sheep and cattle being imported than in 1903. The prevalence of cattle plague in Egypt in 1904 explains this increase, while the failure of the Indian indigo crop in Madras and Bengal brought down the import very considerably. Cotton twist yam and raw silk showed an increase, and raw sugar, mostly from Batavia and the East, was imported to be refined in Egypt for re-exportation.

The export trade from Suez for the year 1904 shows an increase of L.E.47,599 as compared with the previous year. This increase is attributed mainly to the steady demand and the revival of trade generally with the Red Sea and Eastern ports.

The exportation of gum was 6,510 tons, valued at L.E. 146,522. This shows an increase of 2,450 tons, valued at L.E. 58,781, over the previous year. Nearly one-fourth of the above quantity was shipped to France, the remainder being distributed between the United Kingdom, Germany and America. 17,848 tons of Egyptian cane sugar, valued at L.E. 191,149 were exported during the year 1904, less than the previous year. Of the above quantity, 12,217 tons were sent to India and other British possessions in the Far East; Turkish Arabia taking 4,910 tons and Massawah 420 tons. 13,346 kilos of ivory, valued at L.E. 7,721 were exported. This shows a decrease of 1,198 kilos., valued at L.E. 1,316, compared with the previous year. Nearly the whole of the above quantity was shipped to the United Kingdom. 13,346 kilos of ostrich feathers, valued at L.E, 7,721 were exported, as against 5,454 kilos., valued at L.E. 11,217 in 1903; the United Kingdom took nearly the whole of the above quantity. The customs valuation of ostrich feathers has been considerably reduced. This accounts for the increase in weight and the decrease in value for the year 1904. 159,000 kilos, of cotton were exported, valued at L.E. 10,037, more than one-half of which was shipped to India, the remainder to China. 24,808 ardebs of wheat, valued at L.E. 20,484, were exported, as against 26,011 ardebs, valued at L.E. 24,153, in the previous year.

The total value of goods which passed in transit through Suez was L.E. 21,392. Of this amount nearly one-half came from the United Kingdom, and the remainder from China and Eastern possessions.
SAN STEFANO CASINO.
The following is the menu of the dinner to bo given to morrow evening on the occasion of the subscribers’ grand ball.

Conjomml gl»4 en Umo Traite* de mer à le ParUtaone Oamr do filet de bœuf Beatigenoj Pilait de caille* k rBgyptlenne Berooau d’asperge* d’Argenteuil en branche* AijpUlottei do dindonneau rôtie* k la broche 8alado do vaison Ho-nbe Loadlguièr*

Gâteau do SaTOle Fruits Douert
PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.
Brigade General G.M. Bullock, C.B., has completed his inspections in Crete and Cyprus and returned to Egypt to resume command of the forces.
THE SAFETY OF BATHERS.
The Gouvernorat of Alexandria have issued the following notice:—

The Municipality having supplied a number of cork belts with ropes for the use of anyone wishing to go to the help of any person in danger of drowning, the public are hereby informed that these belts are kept, at their disposal, in every Coast Guard Station and small post on the sea-shore between Agami and Aboukir.

A number of light life buoys (to be thrown to any person in distress) have also been ordered, and when received will be placed at the disposal of the public, in the same places and for the same purpose.
Major H.O.D. Hickman, 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, has been granted leave of absence until December 6.
Captain and Brevet Major W.F. Hessey, 2nd Battalion Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, has been granted leave of absence until November 3
Captain John Evans, Royal Inniskilling Fusiliers, has been appointed adjutant, vice the late Captain Carey.
Second Lieutenant G.N. Hubbard has resigned his commission in the Rifle Brigade (The Prince Consort's Own).
We regret to learn that through ill-health Lieutenant Alfred E. Bonham-Carter, King's Royal Rifle Corps, has been temporarily placed on the half-pay list, and we wish him a speedy

recovery.
H.E. De Martino Pasha, director-general of the Daira Khassa, will return to Cairo from Europe on the 3rd proximo.
Mr. L. Landon, assistant engineer of the Sudan Irrigation Department, has been granted two and a half months’ leave of absence.
STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
The Westcott BS. Egyptian arrived to-day from Antwerp, London and Malta with general cargo.
Anglo-American Nile Steamers

et «oralL coMPAmr.

“IfER TRAMPORT OF 00008 »ETWEES ÄLE1M9W» A «AIR? Tfem SmHImge wèAtowir-

A§mU s4 AhtumêHu:— 	

ACUANRA IBMIVOMMBCCI. If

¡¿MM
PROGRESS OF BEYROUT.
ELECTRIC TRAMWAY SCHEME.
(From our Correspondent.)

Beyrout, September 15.

A long-felt need that Beyrouth has required for years is at last to be realised. Locomotion lies at the root of economic development and is essential to the creation of populous industrial and commercial centres, while for already fairly large towns, which like Beyrout, have grown simultaneously in area and population,—Beyrout being like a vast village, several of its houses being surrounded with more or less large gardens, even in central quarters — a superior mode of locomotion, such as an electric tramway, is of vital importance. From east to west Beyrout measures over three miles long and from north to south over two miles wide, and this is considerable for a town whose population is not more than 120,000 souls. The initiator of the present scheme is Mr. Selim Eid, who, indeed, bad conceived the humbler plan of a tramway drawn by animal power, as far back as 1895, and who, after several disappointments and failures, has by his perseverance and energy, finally attained his end, and in a more successful manner than he had ever dreamed of. When Mr. Pilling obtained the concession for the Caiffa-Damascus railway, the so-called débris of which has since been bought up for, the Hamidié-Hedjaz railway, he got in the same firman a secondary concession for a tramway tor Beyrout, but with animal traction. This, concession Mr. Eid bought up, and after many reverses of fortune, he finally found the necessary capital for the realisation of the scheme; but as he was lately going through the, final formalities at Constantinople, a Belgian company, finding apparently in the scheme. alluring prospects of profit, stepped in to oust Mr. Eid's company, and to attain their end, proposed to the Turkish Government the superior mode of locomotion by electricity, and, to further engage the Sultan’s favor, offered to make a donation of L.T. 10,000 to the Hamidié-Hedjaz railway, in which the Sultan takes such a deep and personal interest There was nothing left for Mr. Bid’s company but to concede the same terms. The rival company, however, persisted keenly in the competition, and made a higher hid of L.T. 2,000 more, but thanks to the influence that Mr. Eid had at his back, his rivals’ second offer was declined, on the delicate ground that the matter could not be brought down to the level of a public auction.

Armed with vizierial orders, Mr. Eid came with the engineers to Beyrout to discuss matters with the Vali and the Municipality. Our governor, being an enlightened man, of course lent his full support to a public enterprise calculated to affect so deeply the future prosperity of the town and its environs, and the welfare of the inhabitants. The original plan of the company was to bisect the town with two long lines crossing each other at the square, one to start from near the Lighthouse at Ras Beyrouth, ran by the Syrian Protestant College, then along the Deaconesses road, then the barracks, the square, and on through the Dog River road, up to the bridge near the Lebanese frontier, while the second line is to start from before the Custom House in front of the leading-place, wind round Khan Antoun Bey, then up to the barracks, the square, thence northward along the Damascus Road to Furn El Shebbak, again at the Lebanese frontier. These of course are vital lines, but the Vall remarked with justice that the benefits accruing therefrom would be derived chiefly by the Christian quarters, and as the Moslems were in almost equal proportion it was only fair that they should also receive their share from a public enterprise of this nature, where-fore he proposed that another trank line should be laid along the main road that passes through Al Bashoura, one of the most populous and important Moslem quarters, occupying the south western hill of the town ; to which the concessionaires reasonably ac-quiesced. The Vali then further proposed that a small branch should be extended to the municipal hospital and school of industry, the foundation of which was lately inaugurated with such solemnity on the occasion of the anniversary of the Sultan's accession. These institutions are specially dear to the Vali's heart, for the original conception and the materialisation thereof, such as the collection of fends etc., are mainly his, and he looks to them as memorials, to live after him, of bis philanthropy and his devotion to his Imperial Master. Again the concession-naires acceded to this demand of the Governor, who, encouraged by their complaisance made to them a third proposal, which, however, could not admit of the same obliging acquiescence, inasmuch as it involves an expenditure of about £30,000. This represents the cutting of a straight and wide road from the Custom House right through the old town, emerging on the other side near the Maronite Cathedral of St. George, opposite the convent of the Sisters of Charity. This part of the old town, consisting as it does of an agglomeration of old buildings mostly several stories high, thè cutting of the wide road proposed would necessarily cause the demolition of a great deal of property, and the L.T. 80,000 demanded by the Vali from the concessionaires represents a loan to be contracted by the municipality for expropriation account, and to be sank in a certain term of years. Despite the guarantees of municipal revenues, the concessionaires were quite justified in their reserve, considering the comparative largeness of the sum, and the heavy indebtedness of the municipality. They nevertheless promised to take into consideration the question of a smaller loan, say of
£10,00 This demand of the Vali is indicative of the progressive spirit that actuates his actions, and a great deal of courage on his part, for the execution of such a scheme is likely to create a storm of opposition on the part of the proprietors of those old buildings, most of whom are more or less illiterate Moslems of the old conservative type. Had not one of the pro-gressive and enlightened Valis of Beyrout undertaken a similar task, and actually started the work of enlargement of the Souk E Fashkha, and had finally to stop halfway. The cutting through of that thoroughfare would have shortened distances considerably and proved invaluable to the general traffic. There had been some differences between the engineers and the municipality. The former had proposed to macadamise that part of the road only on which the rails are to be laid, but as our roads are on the whole in a wretched condition and have not even a thin foundation of pebble layer, such partial repair might prove a serious obstacle to the general traffic, on account of the inequalities of level that would result. I have since heard that this point was at last settled satisfactorily . The total length of the lines according to the present plan is to be about ten kilometres, and I believe the company will have the option of certain extensions. The motor force is to be probably hydraulic. It is not known yet which of the waterfalls will be chosen, that of Anteliss or Nahr El Kalb. Both are said to have been found sufficiently powerful for the instalment of the company's electric plant. I have been told by one connected with Mr. Bid that if the company should meet with difficulties, in obtaining the use of either of these waterfalls, they would finally decide on petroleum for the production of electricity. The limit accorded for the completion of the work of construction is said to be one year end four months.

On the basis of snob an agreement as roughly sketched above Mr. Eid and engineers sailed last week for Constantinople with a regular Mazbeda from the municipality. What is needed now is the final Irade, which Mr. Eid has every chance of getting, in view of the influential support that he has from high quarters at the Capital.

Every intelligent man in Beyrout wishes Mr. Eid success in his scheme which if realised will certainly prove an incalculable benefit to Beyrout, and a lasting memorial to the foresight, perseverance, and untiring , of one of its distinguished inhabitants.
LETTER TO THE EDITOR.

We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our correspondents

but we wish 

to »11. *o prtcit — within oirtato mmSbt tt***-K

THE SCANDINAVIAN QUARREL.

To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.

Sir,---I will be pleased if you will publish the following with regard to your article “The Scandinavian Quarrel" in your issue of the 19th inst Sweden has never demanded the

dismantling of the old Norwegian fortresses of Kongsvinger and Fredrikatain, but the question now raised by Sweden concerns the new fortresses constructed by Norway on the frontier since 1890, and which dominate railways and roads on the Swedish territory.

Sweden will no longer tolerate what no other nation in the world would stand ; fortresses which from the frontier’s immediate closeness could cannonade extensive districts of the neighbouring country.

The fortresses of Fredrikstein and Kongs-ringer can be considered as the legitimate protection, but the frontier fortress erected since 1890 as illegitimate threats.

Sweden has not thought it necessary to erect fortresses on the frontier against Norway as a united state but now when the separation of the two countries has to take place, owing to the Norwegian revolution of the 7th June. Sweden considers a neutral zone a better and more justified guarantee of peace between the two countries than the erection of fortresses on the Swedish territory opposite the frontier fortresses quite unneccessarily constructed by Norway.

I have the honor to be, Sir, Yours faithfully, Aug. Silfwerhjelm

Alexandria, September 20.

[Our correspondent forgets that the mete fact that a fortress commands roads or positions in another country does not of itself justify a demand for its demolition by the threatened party. The guns of the outer forts of French Belfort can reach the German

railway and road between Munsterol and Altkirch, but Germany has never demanded the rasing of Belfort Ed E. G.]
BECK & CO’S PIL8ENER BHR
ottAiaahi« frase msufß rnspsetoblj rigs

la (Urna. Auumu a «a* a**u

OttanriNoitto

U.Fioatti, F.MUUjr ***(«*.
CARLTON HOTEL,

NUUr«MMUMN4 BAMLEH’B TA BUON ABLE HOTEL.

NlMlltalM«i4» MMiM

**»«*»«■	twtm n mu—