THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE, SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 23 1905
MOROCCAN CONFERENCE.
GERMAN OBJECTIONS.
AGREEMENT DELAYED.
Paris, September 22.

It is semi-officially announced that it is still believed that the negotiations regarding Morocco will lead to an understanding, but that owing to German demands and objections, especially with regard to policing the frontiers and financial arrangements the agreement will not be concluded as soon as was anticipated.

(Reuter)
BAKU SITUATION GRAVE.
TWELVE THOUSAND TROOPS SENT.

Baku, September 22.

Fifty-three passengers were wounded and one killed in an unsuccessful attempt made by robbers to hold up a train in this district. (R.)

St. Petersburg, September 22.

Twelve thousand troops have gone to Baku, where the situation is grave.	(Reuter)
GERMAN SUBMERSIBLE LAUNCHED.
REPLICA OF FRENCH TYPE.

Paris, September 22.

Consternation has been caused in France by the report that the new German submersible launched at Kiel is almost an exact replica of the last French type. It is believed that the designs have been treacherously sold. (Reuter)
SIGNING OF PEACE TREATY.
COPY FOR THE TSAR

St. Petersburg, September 22. M. Witte’s secretary has arrived bringing with him a copy of the treaty for the Tsar’s signature.	(Reuter)
EVACUATION OF MANCHURIA. THE CHINESE FRONTIER.

St. Petersburg, September 22.

It is stated here that Manchuria will only be partially evacuated, and that several Army Corps will be left on the Chinese frontier. (R.)

St. Petersburg, September 22. The Russians have partially evacuated Manchuria.	( Havas)
RUSSIAN NAVAL PRISONERS.
RODJESTVENSKI BETTER

Tokio, September 22.

The Russian admirals and officers who were taken prisoners have been permitted to return to Russia. Admiral Rodjestvenski has almost recovered. The commander of the Peresviet is dead.	(Havas)
RUSSIAN FORCES IN FINLAND.
St. Petersburg, September 22. The Russian forces in Finland are being considerably increased.	(Reuter)
S.S. CHATHAM TO BE BLOWN UP.
Port Said, September 22.

It is understood that experts sent here recommend the blowing up of the wreck of the S.S. Chatham, which is lying in the Suez Canal	(Reuter)
Port Said, September 23. The Canal Company Commission has decided to blow up the Chatham, probably on Thursday next.	(Reuter)
THE SOCIALISTIC CONGRESS.
Coal Imports. - From the 1st of January to the 21st of September, 746,108 tons of coal were imported into Egypt. Wales sent 399,546, Newcastle 172,193, Scotland 96.815, Yorkshire 48,751, and other places 28,803. During the same period last year 747,533 tons were received.

The Egyptian Directory. — Under this heading in our issue of the 19th inst. we announced that the Egyptian Directory for 1906 would appear in November. We are now asked to draw special notice to the fact that the volume referred to is M. Poffandi's "Indi-cateur Egyptien” and not that published by Messrs Rizzo and Co.
UPHOLDS POPULAR STRIKE.

Jena, September 22.

The socialistic congress has adopted Bebel’s resolution upholding the political strike of the masses.	(Havas)

YACHTING ACCIDENT.

EARL DUDLEY IN DANGER.

Dublin, September 22. i

The Lord Lieutenant, the Earl of Dudley, and Captain and Lady Mabel Crichton were nearly drowned while yacht racing on Lough Erne. Their yacht capsized, but the occupants clang to the boat and were finally rescued by a motor-launch.	(Reuter)

ANOTHER BOMB OUTRAGE.

Varsovia, September 22.

A bomb has been thrown into the Sax Gardens. Several persons are wounded. (H.)
LOCAL AND GENERAL.
All Saints’ Church, Cairo—The Very Rev. Dean Botcher, D.D., who has returned to Cairo from abroad, will preach at All Saints' Church to-morrow morning.
Suez Canal.—6 vessels passed through the Canal on the 20th inst. 5 of which were British and 1 Dutch. The receipts for the day ware frs. 162,849.66, making the total from the 1st inst. frs. 5,447,501.24.
The Brindisi Mail will be made up at the G.P.O., Alexandria, at 8.30 a.m. on Monday for ordinary correspondence. Registered letters must be handed in by 9 p.m. on Sunday, and insured articles, money orders, and parcels by noon on that day.
Stray and Ownerless Dogs found in the Mouski district of Cairo during to-morrow night and at dawn of the 25th inst. will be poisoned by the police. Similar measures will be taken with those found in the Matarieh district during the succeeding night and at dawn of the 26th inst.
Alhambra Theatre.—The Della Guardia dramatic troupe announce a matinee for tomorrow, the programme of which has not yet been decided upon. At the evening performance Tosco will be staged. A benefit performance will be held shortly in honor of M. Ernesto Della Guardia, and several short pieces are billed for this occasion.
A Scoundrel Arrested.—A foreigner was arrested yesterday on the strength of information that accused him of bringing his wife—a young woman whom he recently married in America—to Alexandria with a view to dispose of her for improper purposes. The miscreant who claimed to be an American citizen, but was not, has been imprisoned, and will be tried before the native Tribunal.
The Pyramids Theatre. — The chief attraction at the Pyramids Theatre at present is Professor E. Bellini who gives a number of experiments in telepathy. On such a subject much scepticism is, of course, evinced, and the Professor’s claims to the power of thought-reading are received by the majority perhaps of the audience with incredulity. Though Professor Bellini’s efforts may fail to convince, they are certainly most remarkable, and very interesting.
FRERES DES ECOLES CHRETIENNES. — A "Séance recreative” of the Cercle St Joseph, will be held to morrow afternoon at the Collège St. Joseph, Ramleh, and will include an excellent and varied programme of enter tainments. Amongst the chief items we notice the Italian comic scherzo Non piu sordi in Locanda, the French comedy A Qui le Neveu, and the musical farce Les Deux Aveugles. We trust that the entertainment will receive the support which its object deserves.
PERSONAL AND SOCIAL.
H.H. the Khedive leaves Constantinople on Monday and is expected to arrive in Alexandria next Thursday.
Mahmoud Pasha Sidki, Governor of Alex andria, who left Trieste by the Austrian Lloyd steamer on the 21st inst., is expected to arrive at Alexandria on Monday morning.
PORT SUDAN HARBOUR.
The condition of the Duke d’Andria shows a steady improvement The Duchess is expected to arrive to-morrow by the Florio-Rubattino boat

Dr. Milton is expected to arrive in Cairo on the 27th inst from England.
OPENING BY THE KHEDIVE,

( From our London Correspondent. )

( By Telegraph. )

London, Friday, 1.30 p.m.

I understand that the new harbour at Port Sudan will probably be opened by H.H. the Khedive in seven weeks' time, and that Lord Cromer will also be present at the ceremony.
THE SUCRERIES.
We regret to hear that M. Nourrisson Bey yesterday informed Judge Somerville Took by letter that his work did not permit him to accept the position of agricultural expert in the examination of the affairs of the Sucreries Company, and begged the judge to withdraw his name from the list His refusal to accept the position will delay the publication of the experts’ report, even if MM. Sampaolo and Fourneron complete their examination of the accounts and the plant of the company in time for the meeting of the 4th prox., which is more than a little doubtful

The meeting will probably have to be postponed. The appointment of an agricultural expert cannot be made all at once, and though rumours state that M. Vaast of the New Egyptian Company has been offered the appointment, we understand that up to the time of writing nothing has been definitely decided.

With a view to definitely determining the question of responsibility, M. Dorizon has suggested the return to Egypt of MM. de la Bouglise, Leroux and Poutrel who will arrive at Cairo next Wednesday from Marseilles.
SULTAN OF MOROCCO S EGYPTIAN TROUPE.
On this subject "A1 Moayad” writes as follows.

Early in April 1904, in the very week of the Anglo French agreement concerning Morocco and Egypt, Moulai Abd-el-Aziz engaged a troupe of singers and dancing women under the charge of Moursi Barakat. At the time we remarked that the political and financial situation of Morocco, and above all the internal condition of the country, made us inclined to doubt the news. But we saw the first-class tickets of the troupe, which, by the way, was not the best that Cairo could produce, and we could only express our hope that its harmonies might aid the Sultan to forget his troubles, and bring about friendly relations between Morocco and Egypt Our hopes, however, were vain, and this cure for political anxiety has evidently not been lasting, for once again Moulai Abd el Aziz has engaged the same troupe, this time to calm the agitation aroused by the Emperor William’s visit to Tangiers, and the arrival of one diplomatic mission after another.

The troupe numbers eight persons, as on last year's visit (For the benefit of oar readers we give their names and rôles :—Moursi Barakat, impresario, Badia, prima donna and chief danseuse, Zobeida, eccentric danseuse and comedienne , Zeinab singer and danseuse, Hassan Badri, tenor, Saleh Mohamed, musician, Hassan Ali player of the "oud” and Fangari, chief of the claque.) Even if we can understand the rôle of the first seven members of the troupe it is a little difficult to account for Fangari’s presence, unless the claqueur is summoned to shoot down the protests of M. St Réné Taillandier, or to keep Count von Tattenbach in order.
FORTHCOMING MARRIAGE.
BIRCH-BURTON.

A marriage has been arranged, and will shortly take place, between Mr. Danya Goldney Birch, third surviving son of Mr. and Mrs. Birch, Bleak House, Ramleh, Alexandria, and Miss Lucy Helen B. Barton, elder daughter of the late Mr. and Mrs, J. T. Burton of Ramleh, Alexandria ; the wedding will be quite private, owing to the future bride being in deep mourning.
SALE OF ISMAILIA HOTEL.
M. Imblon, late secretary-general of the Egyptian State Railways, left for Europe yesterday with his family. M. Imblon, who has retired on pension, intends in future to reside in Paris.

We regret to announce the death of Moha-med Safar Bey Yaghen, which took place at Cairo yesterday.

MM. Leroux, de la Bouglise, and Poutrel left Marseilles for Alexandria yesterday.



Among the latest arrivals at the Eastern Exchange Hotel, Port Said we notice : —

Mr. D. Macdonald, Mr. H. Harris, Mr. J. Cunningham. Mr. H. Thomson, Mr. H. N.

I Hartwell, Miss Dill, Mr. J. Barr, Mr. T. J. Coohrane, Mr. D. Ballingall, Mr. J. C. Angerp, Capt. J. B. Satteriay, Miss M. Carter, Mire Kamel, Mr. C. F. Lowenthal, Mr. J. Waker, F. Hauae, Mr. A. M. Timaika, Mr. G.A. Maori, Mr. J. R. Campbell, Mr. H. Hill, Capt, J, 0. Hill
We hear that M. Marini has just sold the Victoria Hotel at Ismailia with all its fittings to the Suez Canal Company for the sum of 30,000 francs. The company agrees to give M. Marini an allowance of 12,000 francs a year daring his lifetime, and a pension of 6,000 francs a year to his wife, should he predecease her.
SAN STEFANO CASINO.
The following is the programme of music to be performed at the casino to-morrow, commencing at 10.30 a.m.

1—Marcho Triomphale—Struhl.

*—Ouyortyro—L* Sohro d'uns naît d'éU—Thotna*.

I-Suit« Algérienne -PaintrSaena,

4 - FontaUi#— Fodom—Giordano.

5—Ballet—Cid — Mwwonct.
STEAMER MOVEMENTS.
NOTES FROM PORT SAID.
CHATHAM TO BE BLOWN UP.
(From our Correspondent.)

Port Said, Friday.

The M.M. Salazie arrived at dawn to-day, having on board M. Tillier, the Chef du Transit, who comes specially to take the chair and direct matters in connection with the unfortunate Chatham incident. Soon after his disem-barcation, a consultation was held at which the heads of Canal Co’s departments assisted. Mr. Harris the special representative of Nobell’s factory was also present, and I understand a decision was arrived at which will become public property very shortly.

On Wednesday after the party had returned from the Chatham, a lengthy meeting was held in the Chief Engineer’s office, but no final decision leaked out, nor has any done so, so far, to-day.

The position of the vessel is the same practically as it was when last I sent notes on the subject except that she is settling down more or less. All sorts of preparations have been made, and from the appearance of things I would not be surprised to bear of something important very soon, when I will communicate with yon.

Later.

From what I learn from various sources I believe it is finally decided to blow the vessel up some time next week, and looking at things from a general point of view, although the actual date is not known, my opinion is it will not occur until after the passage of the Brindisi mail boat

(By Telegraph)

Saturday, 9.30 a.m.

Yesterday’s meeting of the commission of experts in consultation with the heads of the various departments of the Canal Company, finally decided that it would be necessary to blow up the Chatham. I understand that the explosion will not take place till Thursday, in order to let the Caledonia pass safely through with the mails, for India and Australia . A deviation in the fresh water canal is now being constructed as rapidly as possible with a view to minimise the danger to Port Said’s water supply. The explosion will be effected by means of electricity and troops have been ordered up from Cairo.
The blowing op of the Chatham with a cargo of probably more than 100 tons of dynamite, will constitute a world’s record in the history of dynamite explosions. The last record was created at Aboukir, near Alexandria, on the 1st June of the present year, when sixteen and a half tons of dynamite were exploded by Mr. Harris under the orders of the Municipality. No one oau have any conception as to what the force of such an explosion can be ; its consequences may be grave, and it is impossible to say where they will end.

The S.S. Chatham lies about nine miles from Port Said and though perhaps no serious damage will result to the town itself, it is safe to prophecy that a severe shock will be felt, and that windows will be broken, whilst we should imagine that it is quite possible that some of the flimsily built native houses may be damaged. The railway line is in close proximity to the sunken vessel, the rails will probably be loosened, and traffic temporarily suspended. Beyond the damage which will be done to the canal itself, the moat important question to be considered is the danger to the fresh water canal from which Port Said draws the whole of its water supply. The Canal Company is indeed making every effort to avert, or at any rate minimise, this danger by cutting a deviation, but it is almost too much to hope that the fresh water canal will escape destruction at this point, though the work of repair will be much more quickly accomplished than in the case of the maritime canal, and it is to hoped that should Port Said be deprived of fresh water it will only be for a short time.

As regards the effect of the explosion on the ship canal, it is impossible to estimate the extent of the damage. The banks will be blown to pieces for a considerable distance and the canal will, we imagine, be entirely blocked for some three weeks at the least, This will involve the accumulation of 150 vessels or more at either end of the canal, and the loss to trade can well be imagined, for not only will the shipping firms suffer, but those who are awaiting the arrival of cargoes. The mails most, of course, be delayed for as short a time as possible and we suppose that arrangements will be made, whereby they will be conveyed from Port Said to Suez, and vice-versa, by rail, and there re-shipped by other vessels at either end.

PORT SAID AND CALABRIA.

The gala performance held at the Eldorado Theatre on Wednesday, proved a great success, and was largely attended. Two pieces were given by the company, both being exceedingly well received ; they were in Italian. The financial results of the evening were, I believe, most satisfactory, subscriptions having amounted to a very considerable sum, not only from the sale of tickets, but by money-gifts from various residents. The entire committee were present at the performance, and a large number of the British residents attended to swell the already large number in the auditorium.
CONSTANTINOPLE NOTES.
The S.S. Persian Prince left Antwerp yesterday with passengers and general cargo and is due to arrive at Alexandria on or about October 10.

The express Khedivial mail steamship Ismailia will leave Alexandria at 4 p.m. on Wednesday next for Pirseus, Smyrna, Mity-ene, and Constantinople,
Oktalzahl» «mm ovary Roa»«stable Fires X* C.uso, Auuvbbu * rea Soba*. GUsrwto H

LJ.HIUMB7,	r.JMAU* WsAfsnt,

048Mb	U* 1
H. H. THE KHEDIVE.

( From our Correspondent ).

Constantinople, September 18.

H. H. the Khedive while at Vienna paid a visit to the celebrated choral society of Vienna. The president and committee thanked the Khedive most heartily for the honor he had done them, and his Highness replied with a brief extempore speech in which he praised the artistic abilities of the choral society, and particularly mentioned the excellent impression they had left in Egypt- The Khedive then visited the society's museum, which contains a cup presented by the King of Hanover, medals given by Napoleon III., the looks of Mozart's hair, and autograph letters of Weber, Wagner, Meyerbeer, Johann Strauss, and many other famous musicians. On leaving he promised to visit the choral society whenever be passed through Vienna.
NEW S. S. COMPANIES.

A new steam navigation company has been founded at Athens by the well-known Greek builders, MM. Stamatiades, Righinos, and Brontisi. The new line will ply between the various Levantine ports, Alexandria of course included. M. N. Boyiajides, who has been sent to London on a mission which comprises the purchase of vessels, reports that he has just added another steamer, displacing 2,500 tons, to the company's fleet. Meantime M. Giovannidis’ new navigation company, which has started an agency at Rhodes, is on the look oat for steamers to add to its flotilla. The Melpomene is already running between Alexandria and Rhodes, and I expect that other vessels will soon he employed on this service.
PERSONAL.

The many Alexandrian friends of Dr. Zam-baco Pasha will be delighted to hear that the Saltan has conferred the order of the Osmanieh, with brilliants, on this eminent surgeon.

Rini Bey arrived here from Egypt last week to investigate certain questions connected with the pilgrimage to the Moslem Holy Places. He was accompanied by Mr. T,H. Parker.
LETTER TO THE EDITOR.

We do not hold ourselves responsible for the opinions expressed by our correspondents, but we wish, in a spirit of fair play to a11, to permit — within certain necessary limits — free discussion.
TEA AND TRAVEL
BECK & CO’S PILSENER BEER
To the Editor of the Egyptian Gazette.

Sir, — Having considerable experience of ocean travel in different parts of the world, a recent journey home has served to put life into an old grievance, on which I take the liberty of addressing yon.

One hears from time to time of the waning popularity of this or that line of passenger steamers, and confident that the directors of such lines have the interests of their shareholders at heart, I make the following suggestions which if carried out, will, I think, tend to their reinstatement in the public favour.

In brief, Sir, I recommend that a speciality be made of the tea served to passengers.

After one’s morning tub and in the afternoons could one depend upon a cup of good tea daintily served what a boon, it would be !

How popular such a line would become with the fair sex. The harsh memory of many a rough passage would be softened by the reflection "But they did give us delicious tea !”

A cow or cows should be carried or, failing that, the best brands of sterilised milk, and if macaroons were served with the afternoon tea success would be assured,

Yon will observe, Sir, that I have refrained from mentioning any particular line of steamers ! This reticence on my part is not prompted by a desire to spare any one’s feelings. It arises from the knowledge that they are all tarred with the same brush in respect to the fault to which I take exception.

I am, Sir, etc.

G. H. Ludolf.

Assiout 21st Sept.
PASSENGER LIST.
DRPARTURES.

Le paquebot Portugal, des Messageries Ma ritimes parti hier pour Marseille, avait à bord: Mme et Mlle Imblon et enfant, Mustapha Haki pacha, Ismain Haki psoha, Ahmed Haki paoha, M. Cayla, Mme Bailly, M. E Cattaoui, M. Hussein Assem, M» Merci nier, M. et Mme Barbedienne, M. et Mme Thoodoraki et bébé, Mme N. Maorady, M. Cassouli, M. Lévidis, R. P. Corvée, M. et Mlle Angelo Gdanti, M. Shoppee, M. Wilfred Hilpern, M. Meier, §f. 88 passagers de 8me et 4me classes.
CARLTON HOTEL,

BULKELEY (near Alexandria.)

Hotel

PATBONI81D HT TU XZJTB. pan Ttm+m tat F.T. «ia«u. IMtan ta

°****«» T MIUIUN*. I***»
CHRONIQUE FINANCIERE
La semaine qui vient de s’éoonler a été l’nne les pins oalmes qae noas ayons en à enregistrer depuis quelque temps. Las grosses valeurs en

particulier, telles que la Banqae Nationale, .’Agrioole, la Dalia, la Béhéra et a Delta Light ont été à près complètement délaissées. Les valeurs nouvellement émises, le Trust, l'Invest-ment et les Estâtes qui avaient fiait preuve d'une grande activité les semaines précédantes, ont elles-mômes cédé sons le poids des réalisations. Somme toute, pourtant, les oonrs se sont bien maintenns et si pour certains titres la ôlôture a lien en baisse, nombre d’autres accusent une reprise sensible. De oe dernier nombre font partie la Banque d’Athènes, la New-Egyptian, les Markets, l’Anglo-Amerioan Nile et les Sucreries.

Ces dernières ont été à l’ordre dn jour pendant tonte la semaine. Il semble bien, comme c’est le oas d’ordinaire dans tons les kraoha, qu’elles aient atteint d’ans seule traite leur couru minimum à 39 franos deux on trois jours après le suicide de Grenier. Depuis, en dépit de nombreuses réactions, elles n’ont oessé d'aller de l’avant Dès samedi dernier, avant môme qn’on sût rien dn bilan on du oonoordat préventif,le ooon était remonté a 43f Maintenant qne le oonoordat préventif a été aooordé, il va sans dire qne la situation ne peot que s’améliorer. Elles ont clôturé à 54 acheteurs.

L’Anglo-Amerioan Nile qui est fortement intéressée dans la Menzrieh Company, après être restée toute la semaine inactive, a olôturé aveo une hausse subite de 1/8 à 5 11/16, en prévision de l’inangaration en octobre prochain de la ligue Matarieh-Port-Saïd.

En sympathie aveo le marché de Paria qui donne le ton pour oette valeur, la Banqae d’Athènes remonte de 129 h 180 1/2, aveo affaires. Paris cote 183.

De 24/9 les Egyptian Markets montent graduellement jusqu'à 25/6 en prévision de la prochaine ouverture des marchés à la suite de la disparition presque totale de la peste bovine en Egypte-

Une autre valear, depuis longtemps oubliée, reprend peo à peu. Ce sont les Cotton Mills qui dôtorent à 6/~.

L'investment et le Trast débutent à 1 18/82 et olôfcarent vendeurs à oe cours.

Après s’ôtre relevés un matant à 1 11/32, les Estâtes retombent bientôt à 1 6/16, pour olô-turer vendeurs à oe prix.

L’Oasis qui avait ouvert à 11/4 finit à 1 8/16, en baisse de 1/16 pour la

Une baisse sensible se produit sur las Tramways d’Alexandrie : les Privilégiées tombent à 159 1/2 et les Dividendes à 816-320. Cette ré-aotion n’a rien qoi la justifie, puisque les re-oette8 vont sans cesse en augmentant et que l’entreprise ne peut que prospérer aveo l’ao oroissement de la population et l'agrandissement de la ville. Las bains dn Mex qui vont disparaître de leur emplaoement aotuel pour frire plaoe à la ligne dn Mariout seront remplacé os dès le printemps prochain par on nouvel établissement moni de tons les perfectionna en ts modernes. Une commission s’est transportée an Mex hier matin pour ohoisir le nouvd emplaoement destiné à la Sooiété des Tramways pour son hôtel et see bains.

L’Ordinary Khedivial Mail hausse de 28/9 à 24/9, mais elle retombe ensuite en dôture à 23/6.

La Filature réaotionne de 29/82 à 7/8,

La Banque Nationale débute à 27 6/8 et atteint il 18/16 ponr revenir en clôture b

27 5/8.

L’Agrioole ouvre à 14 8/8, atteint 14 7/16 et retombe à 14 18/32, .

Après avoir repris de 27 11/16 à 28 1/4, la Drira retombe à 28, prix auquel elle clôture vendeurs.

La Nungovioh ouvre à 10 7/16, atteint 10 1/2 et retombe à 10 7/16.

Une nouvelle banque franoo-égyptienne vient d'ôtre fondée d’après la loi anglaise^ aveo un ospitai de £50(v 09 en actions de £6 chacune. Le ospitai est déjà intégralement sousorit et fej actions fout dès à présent une prime de £1 1/4 à la Bouree de Paris, Cette Banqae se rattache an Crédit Mobilier de Paris et au Credito Mobiliare d’Italie.

D'autre part, nue nouvelle oompagnie dont le pro3peotus paraîtra en Ootobro prochain vient de se constituer au Caire, sous le nom de ‘•Anglo-E^yptian Land Allotment Company” aveo Sir William Willoocks pour président Le capital est fixé à £500,000 divisé en actions de 4£ ohaonne. La nouvelle société a pour but exolusif l’aohat de terrains à diviser en lots plus on moins grands poar ótre vendus aux fellahs et la looation de terres à sous-louer de môme aux fellahs après leur amélioration.

Alexandrie, le 22 Septembre 1905.
BULLETIN DB LA BOURSH
( AukmrJImi àmidi* dm*)

La baisse et rinaotion ne font que s'aoœn' tner. Tout as lea fluotuationa de la oote indi* qnent an nouveau recul.

Il faut, cependant, en exoepter U Banque d'Athènes dont le oonrs s’aranoe d’un coup de 180 1/2 à 184 1/2.

La National Bank fléchit de 27 5/8 à 27 9/16.

On offre l’Agriocle à 14 8/8, soit une baiare de 1/32.

Lea pelitea valeur*, l'Investmeut et le Trust, qui avaient résisté jusqu'à maintenant, fléchissent aussi de 118/82 à 1 8/8.

Quant aux Estâtes, ils sont tombés un moment à 17/82 à.la suite d’une panique injustifiée (prétendueperted'un procès da préemption). A peine la nouvelle exacte est-elle arrivée ici a ne le cours a immédiatement repris à 19/82. Les transactions ont été considérables.

La Land Bank tombe aussi da 9 11/16 à 9 5/8, la Daïra de 98 à 97 7/8, U New Egyptien de 84/6 à 84/8, ks Markets de 25/6 à 96/8 et rOrdinarjr Khédivial Mail de 21/6 à 98. ,

Après avoir ouvert à 55, ks 8oercriss çef réactionné jusqu'à 68,
